勇敢者游戏2：再战巅峰
离开这里 去见你们
Leaving this to come see you.
我等不及了
And I can't wait.
(离开这一切来见你 我等不及了!)
呼
Whew.
(玛莎: 我很期待!)
(纽约大学)
出租车! 这边
Taxi! Over here.
出租车！
Taxi!
抱歉 抱歉 抱歉
Sorry. Sorry. I'm sorry.
不好意思
Excuse me. Excuse me.
(冰箱: 周六诺拉小馆见?)
- 吉尔宾  -啊！
- Gilpin! - Ahh!
牙膏还没摆好吗?  你在玩手机吗？
You still on the toothpaste? Are you on your phone?
我只是...我今晚将放假回家了 所以...
I'm just... I'm going home for the holidays tonight, so...
你觉得是今晚放假吗?
Does it look like tonight to you?
对于我而言 你像是今天就放假了
Because to me, it looks like today.
把牙膏摆放好 --好的 抱歉
- Finish the toothpaste. - Okay. Sorry.
爸爸 我们回家了！
Dad, we're home!
我在厨房里！
I'm in the kitchen!
珍 斯潘瑟
Jan, Spencer!
我在厨房里！
In the kitchen!
爸爸 你在梯子上吗？
Dad, are you on a ladder?
你在做什么？爷爷
- What are you doing? - Grandpa.
你说我在干什么？快下来
- What's it look like? - Get down.
我在帮你换灯泡
I'm changing your light bulb.
我才走10分钟 你就非得爬梯子吗？
I leave for 10 minutes, you're climbing ladders?
我认为你不应该做这些事
Don't think you should be doing that.
怎么 你认为我连灯泡都换不了吗？
You think I can't change a light bulb?
好的 这儿
- Okay. - There.
没事 没事 没事
Ugh! No, no, no.
我站好了 没事
- I got it. I'm fine. - Okay.
嘿 孩子！
Hey, kiddo!
嘿 纽约怎么样？
Hey, how's New York City?
很好的 -那学校呢？
- It's great. - How's school?
还不错 -你怎么样？
It's okay. How you doing?
我好着呢 我都不知道我在这里干什么
I'm terrific. I don't even know what I'm doing here.
你刚做完髋部手术 需要恢复
You're recovering from hip surgery.
嘿！！我很快就会离开这里的
Meh! I'll be out of here in no time.
这里又不是监狱
It's not a prison.
我就想回我的公寓去
I wanna get back to my apartment.
有那么糟糕吗？—你的公寓？没错 哪里糟糕透了
- Is that so terrible? - Your apartment? It's terrible.
这里真的很冷吗？
Is it really cold in here?
对  楼下的暖炉彻底不行了
The downstairs heater isn't working.
修理工明早才能过来 -屋里冷得像个破冰箱似的
- The guy's coming in the morning. - It's like a goddamn icebox.
你给迈洛打电话了吗？
Did you ever call Milo?
什么？没有
What? No.
爸爸 他给你打了五个电话了 你给他回一个不行吗？
Dad. He's called five times. Just call him back.
我才不要给他回电话呢 因为我不想跟他说话
I'm not calling him back. I don't wanna talk to him.
来吧 我来帮你放行李
Come on, I'll help you with your bags.
哦 原来你住这里
Oh, you're staying in here.
我们是室友
We're roommates.
对 其实我可以去楼下 睡沙发上
Yeah. I could just stay downstairs on the couch.
什么？别说傻话.-如果你乐意的话
- What? Don't be ridiculous. - If you want, yeah.
你得住好几周呢 没事的
It's a couple weeks. It's gonna be fine.
快进来吧 把这里当成自己的家
Come on in. Make yourself comfortable.
哦！你真是
- Oh! You're gonna... - Whoa!
没事吧？-别跟你妈妈说！
- You okay? - Don't tell your mother!
这个插这里.好了
This goes there. There.
那个插那里
That's in there.
(玛莎: 算我一份!)
好了 我们来试试 -好了 我们来看看
- All right, let's try it. - Okay, let's see.
(冰箱: 唷 史宾赛! 你在吗?)
好了 那里有了
All right, so there's that.
这里也搞定了 这里搞定了.
There's this. There's this.
蓝灯变红灯 还有绿灯
The blue light, the red, the green light.
(明天见)
哦！看看你们两个 太温馨了？
Oh, look at you two. How sweet is this?
好了 我明天早起上班那时候估计你们还没有起床
Okay, I have to leave for work before either of you gets up.
不过修暖炉的上午过来
The heater guy's coming in the morning.
我10点要去跟朋友们一起吃午餐
I'm gonna meet my friends for brunch at 10.
那挺好的 你们去哪里吃？
That'll be nice. Where are you going?
UM...诺拉丝-为什么去那家？
- Um... Nora's. - What are you going there for?
布兰特福有那么多餐厅
All the restaurants in Brantford,
你们非得去那家吗？-不是我选的
- you gotta go to that one? - I didn't pick.
爸爸 这有什么关系？都过去多年了 好吗？
What difference does it make? It's been years.
宝贝 我爱你 真高兴你回家了
I love you, honey. I'm so glad you're home.
我也爱你 妈妈
Love you too, Mom.
人老了就是一团糟 谁说不是你都别信
Getting old sucks. Don't let anybody tell you any different.
那那个小女朋友还谈着吗？
You still got that little girlfriend?
没有
No.
我们已经不在一起了.
We're not together anymore.
应该算分手了.
I don't think.
谁甩的谁 是她还是你？
Was it her or you?
说来复杂.-说来听听
- It's complicated. - Try me.
看我能不能理解.
We'll see if I can understand.
好 我们最开始走到一起时
Well, when we first got together,
我们俩...
we were...
可以说 跟现在是两个不同的人.
sort of different people than we are now.
我想 去年我过得...
I mean, last year was...
很迷乱的
amazing.
我是读到高中的高年级.
I was a senior in high school.
还有个女朋友
I had a girlfriend.
好吧 我终于搞清楚了我究竟是谁
Like, I finally figured out who I was or something.
嗯
Mm.
我猜我只是想找回那时的感觉
I wish I could just feel like that again, I guess.
我也不知道
I don't know.
异地恋不容易维持
Long-distance relationships are hard.
我知道大家都这么说 但是 原来真是这样.
I mean, I know everybody says that, but turns out it's true.
我能给你一点小小的建议吗？你听我说
Can I give you a little advice? Listen to me.
每一天在每一节地铁车厢里
Every single day on every single subway car,
都有一大群纽约的姑娘.
there's lots of ladies in New York City.
她们当中的五分之一 我将娶回家 这是毫无疑问的.
And one in five of them, I would marry, no questions asked.
这是你生命中最好的一段时光.
This is the best time of your life.
是吗？-当然是了.
- It is? - Yes, it is.
所以振作起来！因为没有比这个更好的时光了.
So pull it together! It doesn't get any better than this.
以后就都是下坡路了.
It's all downhill from here.
勇敢的石头
Bravestone.
(尤曼吉)
(诺拉小馆)
嘿！
Hi!
耶 耶 耶！
Yay, yay, yay!
哦——！哦 你好吗？
- Ooh! - Oh, gosh, how are you?
我的天呀 你今天真漂亮.-谢谢！
- Oh, my God, you look amazing. - Thank you.
ho,ho,ho!
Ho, ho, ho!
冰箱 -冰箱！
- Fridge. - Fridge!
过来 -哦——！
- Come here. - Ooh!
所以我们建了两个月的房子
So we were building houses for two months,
然后在回家的路上 我们去了哥斯达尼加.
and then on the way home, we stopped in Costa Rica,
那里也很神奇
which was also amazing.
太有意思了 我真为你高兴.
That is so awesome. I am so happy for you.
太酷了！
That is so cool.
所以 “小玛” 我们现在是不是要这样叫你？
So, "M," that's what we're supposed to call you now?
好了 你用不了这么叫我
You don't have to. It's just a nickname.
这是我的一个大学同学起的
One of my college friends gave me that.
你们不用这么叫我.
You don't have to call me that.
小玛 我喜欢 真火啦！
M. I love it. It's so hot.
好了 -不过你还有斯潘瑟
- Okay. - But you and Spencer,
你们还没有...?      yeah,不.嗯 我们...
- you're still not...? - Yeah. No. Um, we're...
我们都想冷静一下
We're still, like, taking a break.
顺便问一下 他人在哪儿？
Where is he, by the way?
不是吧
Eh, Christ.
你来干什么 迈洛？
What do you want, Milo?
很高兴见到你.
Nice to see you too.
是的 我很乐意进屋去喝杯咖啡.
Yes, I'd love to come in for a cup of coffee.
谢谢你邀请我.
Thanks for asking.
你介意我加一些鸡蛋吗？
You mind if I make some eggs?
你干什么都行 我不介意.
Do whatever you want. I don't care.
只不过你得快点 我可没有一整天的时间
Just hurry up. I don't have all day.
你要出门吗？
You going somewhere?
嗯 um   ?
Have, um...?
你和斯潘瑟联系多吗?
Have you been in touch with Spencer much?
是的
Yeah...
你想知道什么？
You know what?
其实还真的不多
Not really, actually.
我经常给他发短信 但是他总是不怎么回复我.
I text him a lot, but he doesn't always text me back.
我明白 -我只是...
- I know. - It's just...
我只是最近特别忙
I've been crazed lately
你也知道 要上课啊 要做练习啊
with, you know, classes and practices,
在周末还要打比赛.
and I got games on the weekends.
嗯 肯定的 肯定的.
Yeah. Totally. Totally.
我明白 我就是...我一直有点担心他.
I've just... I've been... I've been a little worried about him.
好吧 看看吧 那家伙真的去了哪儿？
Okay, look, where...? Where is this guy? For real.
好吃吗？
Good?
-切 -你的切是什么意思？
- Meh. - What do you mean, "Meh"?
切!你到底想怎么样？
Meh! What do you want already?
我曾经停地打你的电话
You've been calling and calling.
你在15年后又突然出现
You show up out of the blue after 15 years.
为什么？就是因为你想要煎鸡蛋吗？
Why? 'Cause you wanna make some eggs?
你还记得我们刚开业的时候吗？
You remember when we first opened,
我们雇了小洗碗工 叫莫里斯
we had that little dishwasher, Morris?
对   我当然记得莫里斯
Yeah, of course I remember Morris.
他上晚餐的班
Worked the dinner shift.
一周上六天  大多时候都是2点钟才下班
Six days a week, 2 in the morning most nights.
-洗碗工嘛 -小莫里斯
- The dishwasher. - Little Morris. Mm.
他总是最后清洗平底锅
He wouldn't even touch those saucepans until he was done
一定要先把池子里的餐具都洗干净
with every single utensil in the bin.
他活干的得很好
Yeah, the man knew his craft.
小莫里斯
Little Morris.
你给我…
Well, get... Wha...
你有话就说  行吗?
Just get to it, would you?
你说话总是喜欢这样子绕弯子
I mean, it's always the scenic route with you.
我知道想要什么  想要我道歉
I know what you want, you want to apologize.
不过我很遗憾告诉你  我没有兴趣
And I hate to tell you, I'm not interested.
你认为是我应该向你道歉吗?
You think I'm supposed to apologize?
修暖炉的来了
Oh, heater guy.
-埃迪爷爷?  -安东尼?
- Grandpa Eddie? - Anthony?
是的  先生  是我
Yes, sir, it's me.
安东尼!
Anthony!
你好吗?
How are you?
快进来  快进来
Come on in. Come on in.
-你怎么样? -老了就是一团糟
- How you doing? - Oh, getting old sucks.
谁说不是你都别信
Don't let anybody tell you any different.
这是玛莎和贝瑟妮
Heh, heh. Oh, uh, this is uh, Martha and-and Bethany.
这是斯潘瑟的外公 埃迪
This is Spencer's grandfather, Eddie.
玛莎? 你就是那个小女朋友
Martha? You're the little girlfriend.
-额… -早上好
- Uh... - Morning!
早上好  先生  不好意思打扰你们了
Morning, sir. Sorry to barge in on you.
你没打扰  他才打扰我
You're not barging. He's barging.
我是迈洛 沃克
Milo Walker.
等等  迈洛? 迈洛和埃迪餐厅的迈洛吗
Wait, Milo? Like... Like Milo and Eddie's.
-很高兴认识你 -天哪  我爸说
- Pleased to meet you. - Man, my dad said
你们的餐厅全场最好
you guys had the best restaurant.
其实我们刚刚还在那里  它现在叫诺拉家
We were just there. Well, it's called Nora's now.
诺拉家? 它连餐厅都算不上
Pfft, Nora's. It's barely even a restaurant.
现在更像是个吃早餐的地方
It's more like a breakfast place now.
你是和斯潘瑟一起来的吗?
Were you with Spencer?
没有  其实我们是来找他的
No, we came here looking for him, actually.
你们饿了吗  锅里还有鸡蛋
You all hungry? Eggs on the griddle.
-也行我可以看看 -小子  光看看可不够
- Might have to take a look. - Hey, man, you can do more than take a look at it.
好吧  好吧  好吧
All right, all right. My man.
-你需要帮忙吗? 我看起来需要帮忙吗?
- Whoa. Do you need a hand? - Do I look like I need a hand?
玛莎
Martha?
嘿
Hey.
他在哪
Where is he?
-你们听到了吗 -听到了
- Do you hear that? - Yes.
你听见什么声音吗
You hear something?
可能是暖炉  它坏了
It's probably the heater. It's broken.
它怎么会在这里
How did it even get here?
我不知道
I don't know.
也许…我不懂
Maybe he... I don't know,
也许他又回去捡回来了
maybe he went back for it or something?
是不是想修好它
Is he trying to fix it?
为什么会有人想修好这东西
Why would anyone try to fix that thing?
我不知道
I don't know.
我也不知道  也许他去买零件什么了
I don't know. Maybe he went to buy parts or something?
行吧 听着  我再给他打个电话
Okay, look, I'm calling him again.
我敢说什么事…都没有
I'm sure everything's... fine.
14条短信和4个未接电话
Fourteen texts and four missed calls.
我觉得他没出去
I don't think he went out.
我想…
I think...
我想他又进去了
I think he went back in.
不  不  不
No, no, no. No, no, no, no, no...
-什么  不  为什么 -不是吧
- What? No. Why...? - Come on, man!
他为什么要这样做
Why would he do that?
你还记得里面什么情况吗
Remember what it was like?
-我被一头该死的河马吃掉了 -我被一块蛋糕害死了
- I got eaten by a fricking hippo! - I got killed by a piece of cake!
伙计们  伙计们
Guys, guys.
他要怎么出来
How is he gonna get out?
他要拿到一块绿色的宝石
Uh, he's gotta take the... The green jewel.
然后把它放到一座雕像上
And stick it back in the statue thing.
靠他自己吗
By himself?
我们得去救他
We gotta go get him.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
-我和你一起去 -你们都傻了吗
- I'm coming with you. - Are you out of your minds?
我们可以的  我们去过  知道会发生什么
We can do this. We've been there. We know what to expect.
我以后不能跟白人玩了
I gotta stop hanging out with white people.
真不知道我什么毛病
I don't know what's wrong with me.
她说得对 我们之前玩过 最后还赢了
She's right. We played before and we won.
我们差点死在那里
We barely survived!
你知道他会进去救你的
You know he would do it for you.
救我们任何一人
For any of us.
小心  它看起来已经坏了
Be careful. It looks pretty busted.
欢迎来到尤曼吉
Welcome to Jumanji.
什么  我们还没有选角色呢
What...? We haven't even picked our guys yet!
什么
What?
好吧  好吧  又来了 我讨厌这部分  没事的 好了
Okay, okay. Here we go. Oh, I hate this part. All right. Okay.
怎么会这样
This is not happening!
伙计们
You guys?
不
No!
我这是
Am I...?
难道  真不敢相信
Is it...? I can't believe...
Oh!
是她
Oh, it's her.
我还是她
I'm her.
斯潘瑟
Spencer.
斯潘瑟?
Spencer?
这是什么情况
What in tarnation?
我在哪里
Where am I?
这是什么鬼地方
What the hell is this?
不会吧
Oh, my God.
埃迪?
Eddie?
-你又是哪位 -我是迈洛 沃克  你是谁
- Who the hell are you? - I'm Milo Walker. Who are you?
迈洛?
Milo?
什么情况  怎么…
What on earth? What...?
-什么鬼…? -我的天
- What the...? - Oh, my.
先等一下
Wait a minute.
老天啊
Oh, Lord.
-这不可能 -抱歉
- This isn't happening. - Pardon me?
-你是谁 -你是斯潘瑟的外公
- Who are you? - You're Spencer's grandfather.
-对 不骗你 -而你是迈洛
- Yeah, no kidding. - And you are Milo.
我当然是
I certainly am.
我是玛莎  斯潘瑟的…
I'm Martha, Spencer's...
你是他的小女朋友
You're the little girlfriend?
-小心! -什么
- Look out! - What?
-啊 噢 -哦 天哪
- Ah! Oh, oh! - Oh, Lord.
真是痛死我了
That hurt like a goddamn...
-贝瑟妮 -什么  我不是
- Bethany? - What? I'm not...
不
No.
不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no...
啊
Yo!
不  不  不  怎么会这样
Oh, no, no, no. This can't be happening!
冰箱
Fridge?
是的  我是冰箱  见鬼了
Yes, I'm Fridge, goddamn it!
开什么玩笑
The hell, man?
好吧 看来什么情况不对
Okay. Okay, something went wrong.
你说呢
You think?
我的天
Holy...
等等  如果我是
Wait. If I'm...
那你是… 斯潘瑟?
Then you...? Spencer?
为什么今天每个人都叫我斯潘瑟
Why does everybody keep calling me Spencer?
不  他是埃迪爷爷  而那位  是迈洛
No, that is Grandpa Eddie. And that, heh... is Milo.
很高兴认识你
Pleased to meet you.
什么鬼
What?
那贝瑟妮呢  还有斯潘瑟
Then where's Bethany? And where's Spencer?
我不知道  好吗
I don't know! Okay?
游戏没有让我们选角色  所有…
The game, it didn't let us pick our avatars, so...
-因为游戏机坏了 -对 行了
- Because it's busted! - Yeah, okay.
我们死了吗
Are we dead?
其实 我也在想这个问题
You know, I was just wondering the same thing.
我是不是死了
Did I die and turn into
还变成一个个子小 身体壮的童子军
some kind of a small, muscular Boy Scout?
-我们没死 -那怎么回事
- We're not dead. - So then what's going on here?
好吧  虽然听起来很奇怪
Okay, this is gonna sound very, uh, strange,
但是我们在一个电子游戏里  它叫尤曼吉
but we are in a video game called Jumanji,
我们用的身体是游戏里的角色
and we are in the bodies of video game characters, heh.
我们以前来过一次  我和冰箱
And we've been here before, Fridge and I.
-但上一次我是你 -嗯
- Last time, I was you. - Mm.
-什么 -我们在游戏里
- Huh? - We're in a game!
我们得找到斯潘瑟 因为他也在这
We gotta find Spencer 'cause he's in here too.
斯潘瑟？是的
- Spencer? - Yes.
他也在？没错
- He's here? - Yes.
斯潘瑟 埃迪的孙子？
Spencer, Eddie's grandson?
是的 斯潘瑟
Yes. Spencer.
-他也在？ -是
- He's here too? - Yes!
他在这 我们得找到他
He's here, and we gotta find him.
所以它有点像捉迷藏
So it's like a hide-and-go-seek situation.
我不是抓的那个人
I'm not "it."
嗯
Hm...
我屁股现在好点儿了
My hip feels pretty good now.
哇 就像关节里上了润滑油
Oh, my joints feel like butter.
-嗯 嘿 快看  -哇偶
- Oh, yeah, look at those. - Wow.
快看 看我多灵活
Look at these. Look at what I got.
-嗯 我们有些小麻烦 -这还用你说？
- Uh, we have some issues here. - You're telling me this?
我成了土肥圆大叔
I'm the old fat dude.
我这次回来后 更倒霉了
I came back, and things actually got worse.
至少上次我还是黑人
At least last time I was still black.
嘿 看看这小家伙
Well, look at this little fella.
喂那个 嘿
Hello there. Heh.
沃克先生 别离水太近！
Mr. Walker, don't get too close to the water!
-快离开那里 ！-不好意思 你说啥呢？
- Get away from there! - I'm sorry, what'd you say now?
嘿！啊！
Hey! Ahh!
给我滚回去
Get on out of here!
发生啥了？
What just happened?
见鬼 那是什么？
What the hell was that thing?
嘿 那是河马 嗯
Well, that there was a hippopotamus. Mm-hm.
它们速度超级快
And they are awfully fast.
比那马还快 叫人不敢相信
Faster than a horse, if you can believe that.
而且撕咬时凶猛可怕
And they've got an awful ferocious bite.
怎么样？你瞧 有意思的是
How about that? You know, the funny thing is,
我不记得
I don't remember...
我有这么了解河马 到这会才知道
knowing much about hippos until right now.
你真是个动物学家
You're a zoologist.
-不好意思 什么？-我们在佛罗里达？
- I'm sorry, what now? - Are we in Florida?
听 这是个危险的地方
Just listen. This is a dangerous place.
超级危险
Crazy dangerous.
但是 玛莎和我 我们之前来过这
But Martha and I, we've been here before.
我们知道自己在干啥 你得保持警惕
We know what we're doing. You gotta stay alert all the time.
要是我靠近水边 我会盯着水面 听到了吗？
If I'm near water, I got one eye on the water, you hear me?
你甚至需要有双眼睛紧盯背后
You got to have eyes in the back of your...
神呐
Oh, God.
他到底出什么事了
What in the Sam Hill just happened to him?
这不可能吧
Shut the front door.
见鬼 你怎么了？
What the hell happened to you?
操
Damn!
飞机？
A plane?
啥？快！跟上！
What? Come on! Follow me!
快 快走 快走 跟上
Come on, let's go. Let's go. Follow us.
欢迎来尤曼吉
Welcome to Jumanji.
-为啥他在飞机里？-我不知道
- Why is he in a plane? - I don't know.
别傻站着了 快上来
Well, don't just stand there. Hop in!
系上安全带 没有多余的时间了
Strap in. There's no time to spare.
勇石博士 著名的考古学家
Dr. Bravestone, famed archeologist
国际探险家
and international explorer,
你回来了我很高兴
I'm so glad you've returned.
一直再等你回来
I've been so anxious for your arrival.
- 你跟我说话呢？-对
- You talking to me? - Yes.
再说一次 尤曼吉又一次陷入危险
Once again, Jumanji is in great peril,
只有你能帮我们
and only you can help.
奈杰尔 我们再找一个朋友
Nigel, we're looking for our friend.
-你有没有看到谁..？ -鲁比 · 朗德豪斯 少男杀手
- Have you seen, like, anyone...? - Ruby Roundhouse, killer of men,
欢迎来到尤曼吉
welcome to Jumanji.
-少男杀手  -对 我杀男的
- "Killer of men"? - Yeah, I, uh... I kill guys.
很高兴你回来了
I'm so glad you've returned.
一直期待您的到来
I've been so anxious for your arrival.
-这小子咋啦？  -我最最亲爱的耗子
- What's with this fella? - My dearest Mouse,
你肯定记得我
surely you remember me.
奈杰尔?布林斯利为您服务
Nigel Billingsly at your service.
嘿 奈杰尔 我就觉得是你
Hey. Nigel, I thought that was you.
他是…呃 叫什么来着
He's a... Uh, what is it called?
-NPC 就是非玩家角色 -他不是真人
- NPC, a non-player character. - He's not a real person.
他只能说固定的几句话
He only has a limited number of things he can say.
噢 我朋友卡尔也那样
Mm, my friend Carl is just like that.
奈杰尔 我们在找人
Nigel, we're looking for someone.
最近有人来过尤曼吉吗
Has anyone arrived in Jumanji...?
魔幻纪很危险
Jumanji is in great peril.
我在信里说的很详细 布莱伍斯通博士
It's all detailed in the letter I sent you, Dr. Bravestone.
可能你没好好读
Perhaps you should read it aloud.
埃迪爷爷
Grandpa Eddie.
-你有信吗？ -我有信？
- Do you have a letter? - Do I have a letter?
-看看你口袋 -为啥我会有信？
- Check your pockets. - Why would I have a letter?
因为奈杰尔给你写了一封信
Nigel here wrote you a letter.
我没有收到他的信
I didn't get a letter from this guy.
但是我们现在在游戏里
But we are in a video game, and...
我们在游戏里吗？
We're in a video game?
我们死定了
We're gonna die.
-已经死了  -这是地狱吗？
- We did die. - Are we in hell?
-我就知道  -神呐
- I knew it. - Oh, my God.
我在信里跟你说的很清楚
It's detailed in the letter I sent you,
布莱伍斯通博士 你没好好读
Dr. Bravestone. You should read it aloud.
我没收到信！我得跟你说多少次？
I don't have a letter! How many times I gotta tell you that?
噢 不 埃迪 信在你手里
Oh, no, Eddie. It's in your hand.
它是从哪里寄来的？
Where did this come from?
你得留心你手里拿着什么
You got to pay attention to what's in your hand.
也许你该大声读
Perhaps you should read it aloud.
勇石博士 我衷心的希望
"Dr. Bravestone, it is my solemn hope
你能收到这封信 因为
that this letter finds you, for again..."
尤曼吉 因为尤曼吉又一次陷入极大危险之中 我们再次需要你
Jumanji is in grave danger. We need your help at once.
谁啊 怎么回事
Whoa, what's going on here?
这是剧情画面 我们就是这样发现的
It's a cutscene. It's how we find...
待会解释
I'll explain afterwards.
你看 我们最糟糕的噩梦
You see, our worst nightmare
成真了
has come to pass,
因为暴君尤尔根回来了
for Jurgen the Brutal has returned.
没错 那个残酷无情的尤曼吉征服者回来了
Indeed, that most vicious Jumanjian conqueror is back.
并且带着
And he's brought with him
他的野蛮人大军
his savage horde.
他们从他们的扎迈尔山顶的要塞下来
They descended from their fortress atop Mount Zhatmire
一路南下 到了飞鸟部落
and made their way south to the Avian Province,
圣物神鹰宝石就在那里
home of the sacred Falcon Jewel,
戴在部落长老的脖子上
worn around the neck of the village elder.
神鹰宝石为尤曼吉带来了富饶
The Falcon is the fertility jewel of Jumanji,
飞鸟部落的人们
and it has been guarded by the people
已经守护了它千百年
of the Avian Province for hundreds of years.
只要宝石沐浴着阳光
So long as the jewel can see the sun,
河水就会流动 土地就会肥沃
the waters will flow and the land will flourish.
耶！
Yeah!
许多勇敢的灵魂在那天死去,
Many brave souls died that day,
但尤尔根还是得到了他想要的东西
but Jurgen got what he came for.
他把宝石藏在黑暗中
He stowed the jewel in darkness,
不让阳光照到它
hidden from the sun.
干旱降临大地
A drought befell the land.
庄稼干枯致死
The crops dried out and died.
如果宝石不及时归位
And if the jewel is not returned soon,
后果将可能不堪设想
it may be too late.
所以我召唤了您
Which is why we called for you
和您聪明的伙伴们前来
and your brilliant associates.
我知道这会给您带来多大的压力
I understand the enormous weight
勇士博士
that this must carry for you, Dr. Bravestone,
这又是一场多大的冒险
how this adventure is like no other,
因为正是暴君尤尔根
since it was Jurgen the Brutal
杀害了您的父母
who killed your parents.
不 不 不！
No, no, no, no!
-嗯？ - 他杀的勇士博士的父母啊？
- Huh? - He killed Dr. Bravestone's parents?
就是他杀的
- Indeed, he did.
-博士那时候还小 - 太尼玛可怜了
- When the doctor was just a boy. - Oh, well, that's terrible.
我都不想说了：这就是个游戏
I can't say this enough: We're in a video game.
你们必须从尤尔根手里拿到宝石
You must recover the jewel from Jurgen the Brutal
然后放在阳光下
and show it to the sun.
现在他正在北上穿越一片沙漠
He's making his way north across the desert now.
暴君尤尔根  是不是芭芭拉的儿子？
Jurgen the Brutal. Is that Barbara's boy?
大家要记住 游戏通关要寻宝
And remember, the goal is to recover the loot.
须从暴君处得到
To wrest it from the hands of the brute.
如果要想回到现实
And if you wish to leave the game,
你们必须救出尤曼吉 然后大声叫他的名字
you must save Jumanji and call out its name.
不好意思打断一下 谁尼玛又是尤曼吉
Excuse me. Who is Jumanji?
如果我没听错的话 是这姐们儿的姐们儿
Well, if I was listening correctly, that is her sister.
拿去你们的地图
Here's your map.
寻找绿洲 跟着火焰找到沙漠之果
Find an oasis and follow the flame to the desert fruit.
-嗯？- 我没办法在这里降落
- uh? - I can't land here,
所以你们得自己跳下去
so you're going to have to drop in.
-什么？-不 不
- What? - No, no. Nigel...
-我会尽量往下降  -等等
- I'll get as low as I can. - Hold on.
-准备好 -什么叫准备好？
- Get ready. - What do you mean?
我们都没有降落伞
We don't have parachutes.
我们是不是应该...? 啊！
Shouldn't we have...? Ahh!
-你搞什么鬼？ - 祝你们好运
- What the hell? - Good luck.
尤曼吉的命运就在你们手上了
The future of Jumanji is in your hands.
既然没地方降落 为什么要我们坐飞机？
Why did we take a plane if there's nowhere to land?
给我下去吧你们！
And go!
那货真缺德
The hell, man?
这是哪儿？
Where are we?
丛林在哪儿？
Where's the jungle?
我们来这里干嘛？
What are we doing here?
我们必须要冷静下来 好吗？
We've got to keep it together, okay?
-冷静下来？-没错
- "Keep it together"? - Yes.
可这个是全新的游戏关卡
This is a whole new thing.
可事先没人告诉我们啊
Nobody said we'd have to do a whole new thing.
对了 贝瑟妮又咋了？
And by the way, what the hell happened to Bethany?
那么问题来了 这又是新汉普郡的哪个地方？
So, what part of New Hampshire is this exactly?
这可不是新汉普郡 麦洛
We're not in New Hampshire, Milo.
没错 完全正确 这根本不是新汉普郡
That's right. Exactly. Not New Hampshire.
-你们现在有点儿眉目了吗 无头苍蝇们？ -并没有
- You're starting to get it now? - Nope.
我现在完全是晕的 根本不知道咋回事儿
I don't have the foggiest clue what's going on here.
那货一直叫我勇士博士
That guy kept calling me Dr. Braverman,
这不是我骨科医生的名字吗？
which is the name of my orthopedist.
所以我觉得我可能刚又做了个髋部手术
I'm thinking I just had another hip surgery
现在正在恢复中
and now I'm coming out of it.
嘿！你们过来看看！
Hey! Check this out!
看样子 我们必须找到斯潘瑟
Okay. We have to find Spencer.
这样的话 我们只能玩游戏了
To do that, I think we have to start playing the game.
他之前应该也是这么做的 我们先找到斯潘瑟
I'm sure that's what he did. We find him,
一起爆关游戏 然后回家
finish the game, and we go home.
埃迪 你没事儿吧？
Ed, you okay?
你看到了吗？
Would you look at me?
我又回来了
I'm back.
这种身材我多少年没见了...
I haven't looked like this since...
从来没有
Never.
你就从来没有过这种身材
You looked like this never.
你放屁呢？我年轻的时候 身材一级棒
What? When I was younger, I was in great shape.
你以为我不知道你年轻的时候是什么鬼样？
I remember you when you were younger,
你当时可不是这个样子
and... this is not what you looked like.
我觉得我眼睛的颜色有点儿变了
I think my eyes are a different color.
你整个人的颜色都变了 说什么眼睛
All of you is a different color.
我看起来挺帅的 是吧？对吧？
It's a good look on me, huh? Huh?
看吧 他们是在往北走
Okay. They're headed north.
-北方是哪个方位？ - 我知道个屁
- Which way is north? - I have no idea.
-好吧 你要不看下地图？- 行吧 我现在又成看地图的了
- Well, you wanna check the map? - Right. I'm the map guy now.
“找到绿洲 跟着火焰找到沙漠之果”
"Find an oasis and follow the flame to the desert fruit."
跟着火焰找到沙漠之果
Follow the flame to the desert fruit.
你应该知道的吧 上面啥都没有
You know there's nothing on that?
他可以看到 只是你看不到而已
He can see it, you can't.
地图上的每个地方都代表的是不同级别的关卡
Each place on the map is a different level,
走的越远 关卡越难
and the levels get harder as we go.
这个鬼地方叫...
This one is called...
“沙丘”
"Dunes."
这不是废话吗？
No shit.
那是个什么玩意儿？
Who the hell is that?
呃 鸵鸟吧
Oh, that's an ostrich.
-并不觉得 -肯定是的
- Oh, no. - Yes, indeed.
那就是头鸵鸟
That is an ostrich.
有60种鸟类不会飞
The ostrich is a flightless bird,
鸵鸟就是其中一种
one of 60 species.
比如说有企鹅  有鸸鹋  还有几维
You got the penguin, you got the emu, and you got the kiwi.
嘿  嘿  搞笑的是  我都不记得我知道多少种...
Heh, heh, funny thing is, I don't remember knowing...
你是个动物学家
You're a zoologist.
我上次才是动物学家  那可是个重要角色
I was a zoologist last time. It's important.
可能解决它是不是要轻松点儿
Maybe if we could get through this quicker.
对了  还有就是  它们跑起来的速度可达每小时45英里
Well, another thing is, they can run up to 45 miles per hour,
所以它们是世界上跑得最快的两腿动物
which makes them the world's fastest two-legged animal.
你们之前知道吗？有点儿意思呢
Did you know that? Fascinating.
-这得多牛逼啊  -我们必须离开这儿
- What a magnificent creature. - We should get out of here.
你还知道个啥？
What else do you know?
还有个有意思的地方
Here's another interesting fact.
就是它们可是有三个胃神奇吧？
They have three stomachs. How about that?
噢！来吧 干它！
Ah! Come on. Beat it!
不要靠太近了
Don't get so close.
就是个鸟 好吧？来吧 赶紧滚 不要在这儿瞎晃
Just a bird, okay? Come on, get moving. Get out of here.
-还要啥我们还不知道？- 妈的 笨鸟
- Anything else we need to know? - Beat it, bird.
它身上还有个有趣的地方...
Another interesting thing about the ostrich...
我让你赶紧滚 你这蠢鸟
I said scram, you stupid bird!
-就是当受到威胁的时候... -赶紧给我滚！
- ..is when threatened... - Get out of here!
它们会主动发起攻击
...they attack.
噢！
Oh, my!
-埃迪！埃迪！ -我天！
- Eddie! Eddie! - Oh!
他在哪儿啊？是不是挂了？
Where's Eddie? Is he dead?
-挂了  - 瞎说 虽然他挂了
- Yes. - No. Yes, he died,
但挂得很安静
but he's fine.
我是不是罪魁祸首啊？
Did I just kill Eddie...
就因为我说话太慢了...
by talking too slow...
他经常说我这样总有一天会要他的命
like he always said I would?
为啥老有人从天上掉下来？
Why does everybody keep dropping from the sky?
护士姐姐 我现在需要见勇士曼医生 求你了
Nurse, I'm gonna need to see Dr. Braverman right now, please.
谁是你的护士姐姐 行了 大家听着
I'm not your nurse. Okay, listen.
我们手臂上的这些纹身 代表的是我们在游戏里的生命次数
These tattoos on our arms, that is your life count.
每个人有三条命
We each have three lives.
而你跟冰箱都只剩下两条了
You and Fridge each have two left.
如果三条命都用完了
If you lose all three,
大家听好 我们就真得玩儿完了
listen to me, it is game over.
没错 然后你们就真死了  - 死得透透的？
- That's it. You're dead. - Dead like... "kaputski"?
聪明
Yes.
就是透透的
Kaputski.
那尼玛是什么鬼声音？
What the hell is that?
-尼玛不对劲啊  - 快看
- That's not good. - Look.
呃 其实关于鸵鸟还有一件事儿
Oh, there's one more thing about ostriches.
不是吧
Oh, no.
赶紧说！
Say it!
它们都是成群结队行动的
They travel in herds.
我们得赶紧走！
We gotta get out of here!
-上车 出发！ -  快点快点！甩起你们的大粗腿！
- Dune buggies, let's go! - Come on, come on! Shake a leg!
-嘿 等等我 - 为啥我这么慢？
- Hey, wait. - Why am I so slow?
速度 姐儿们们 赶紧上车！
Haul ass, girl. Let's go!
-快点 快点！- 我来了 埃迪
- Come on, come on! - I'm coming, Eddie.
-快走 - 你看见车钥匙了吗？
- Go. - Do you see the key anywhere?
-我天 这车怎么开啊？-我也从来没开过啊！
- Okay, how do I do this? - I've never driven one of these!
没准儿在仪表盘下面
Maybe under the dash.
-按绿色的按钮！ - 按绿色的按钮 快
- Green button! - Green button. Go.
快 快 快走！
Go, go, go!
快 快
Go, go.
我滴个亲娘啊！
Oh, my God!
快
Go.
尼玛你开车技术烂透了
You are a terrible driver.
你在那儿瞎逼逼什么？我们现在不没事儿吗？
What are you talking about? We're fine.
这还尼玛没事儿 你  噢！噢  噢！
Nobody fine. You... Oh! Oh, oh!
噢 别啊！啊 啊！
Oh, no! Ahh, ahh!
我天 救命啊！噢 噢！
Oh, help! Oh, oh!
埃迪 抓紧啊 你千万别松手啊
Hold on, Eddie. Please don't let go.
啊！噢！噢 哇喔！
Ahh! Oh! Oh, wow!
噢 救命啊 啊！
Oh, help. Ahh!
救我 埃迪 噢！
Help. Eddie. Oh!
去尼玛的！
Beat it!
走你！
Get out of here!
我们应该甩掉它们了吧
I think we lost them.
-是吧？- 应该是
- Yeah? - Yeah.
-你没事儿吧？- 没事儿
- Are you okay? - Yeah.
卧槽
Oh, no.
-我天！-我们咋整？
- Ahh! - What do we do?
我也不知道啊 ！
I don't know!
上车！速度！
Get in! Hurry!
哈！一群蠢货！
Ha! Suckers!
-埃迪... - 噢哦
- Eddie... - Uh-oh.
-天喂...      - 哇哦 哇哦！
- Oh, my... - Whoa, whoa!
-我的玉帝爷爷！-我的王母娘娘
- Oh, dude! - Oh, dear.
我们现在咋搞？
What do we do?
咋搞？
尼玛你想要干啥？
What are you doing?
-前面是鸟 前面是鸟 前面是鸟！-鸟！
- Birds, birds, birds! - Birds!
-你特么发什么疯啊？- 它们飞不来
- What the hell, man? - They're flightless birds.
尼玛这车也飞不来啊！
This is a flightless dune buggy!
-噢！-噢 不！
- Oh! - Oh, no!
不 不 不要！
No, no, no!
-我们过不去的 -我们过不去的
- We're not going to make it. - We're gonna make it.
-不 我们过不去的！-我们过不去的
- No, we're not! - We're not gonna make it.
我们做到了
We're gonna make it.
我们过不去的
We're not gonna make it.
这感觉真是好极了
That was fantastic. Heh.
-噢 真是个糟糕的司机-喔...
- Oh, horrible driver. - Whoo...
是的 你看到了那些鸟了吗？你无法打败年轻人
Yeah, you see that, birds? You don't mess with the kid.
就在这儿！
Right there!
你看到我了吗？
Did you see me?
这简直难以置信
I was incredible.
我的意思是说 我救了你 我救了你
I mean, I saved you, I saved you,
当我在开车的时候我把你从一只大鸟那里救了出来
I saved this guy from a bird while I was driving a car.
我就像机器一样无情
I was a machine. I was relentless.
-我是勇者-是的 一直没错 毫无畏惧的
- I was fearless. - Yes. Exactly. Fearless.
这才是勇者 好了 看看这个
That's Bravestone. Okay, check this out.
噢 天哪
Oh, goodness.
怎么会这样？
What the hell?
是你的强项和弱点
It's your strengths and weaknesses.
我是说你的角色
I... I mean your avatar,
勇石博士 强项和弱点
Dr. Bravestone's, strengths and weaknesses.
“无所畏惧”肯定的
"Fearless," check.
“疾跑 攀爬”“回力镖”？
"Speed. Climbing." "Boomerang"?
“男子气概喷发”？
"Smoldering intensity"?
-你有点蠢 -啊？
- It's this stupid face you make. - Huh?
就是这个
There it is.
他可是个老头 你清醒一点
Ew! Ew! Old man. Get it together.
埃迪 你还好吗？心脏病犯了吗？
Eddie, you okay? You having a heart attack?
他的左侧意见损坏了 埃迪 看着我!
His whole left side is shutting down. Eddie, look at me!
-嗯？-很好 你又回来了
- Yeah? - There you go. Now you're back.
“弱点：弹簧刀”
"Weakness: switchblade."
弹簧刀？嗯 这个是新的
Switchblade? Hey, that's new.
上次勇者没有任何弱点
Bravestone didn't have weaknesses last time.
是的 这真让我烦心
Yeah, bugged the hell out of me.
我在想会不会...
I wonder if...
(强项: 空手道 战舞 双节棍)
-“双截棍”？这是个新的-该死 这技能不错
- "Nunchucks"? That's new. - Damn, that's a good list.
麦洛 拍一下你的左边 就像这样 胸部这边
Milo, push on your left, like, chest area.
-我很抱歉 什么？-快点
- I'm sorry, what? - Come on, man.
(强项: 动物学 武器支援 语言学)
嘿！
Hey!
噢 我也有了一个新技能 什么...？
Oh, I got one too. What...?
(弱点: 蛋糕 速度 力气)
我的是“动物学”你们之前说的就是这个
My. "Zoology." That's what you were talking about earlier.
-没错 是的-没错
- Yes. Exactly. - Yes.
是的就是这个 你的角色就是动物学家
Your avatar is a zoologist.
你知道的 我侄子麦克斯韦是兽医
You know, my nephew Maxwell is a veterinarian.
-太棒了...-“语言学？”
- What a fascinating... - "Linguistics"?
-我上次没有这个-研究语言的学问
- I didn't have that last time. - The study of languages.
说得通 他要学习语言
Makes sense. He studies the entire language
否则说话老是讲不到点子上
on his way to the point.
总之 他32岁了 还是35岁？
Anyway, he's 32. Or is he 35?
时光飞逝
Time does fly.
好吧 让我们早点弄完吧
Okay, let's get it over with.
(强项: 地图学 考古学 几何学)
(弱点: 耐力 热浪 太阳 沙子)
老天一定是在跟我开玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
额 几何学...
Well, geometry is...
-也是新的-是的
- Is new. - Yeah.
谁不想在几何学上学得更好呢？
Who wouldn't wanna be better at geometry?
缺点是 “耐力”
And for weaknesses, "Endurance."
还有吗？我看看 “高温 太阳 沙子”
And what else? Let's see, "Heat, sun and sand."
这根本不是问题 好像我们现在不是在
Shouldn't be a problem. It's not like
最令人讨厌的沙漠里一样
we're in the middle of a goddamn desert or anything.
这个家伙怎么回事？要他有什么用
What's the point of this guy? Who even needs this guy?
他可以看地图
He can read the map.
你说得很容易 你还会双截棍呢！
Easy for you to say, you got nunchucks!
我一天训练四个小时 坚持了六个月
I've been training four hours a day for six months.
结果你们看看我！
Now look at me!
这鬼地方热死了！
Man, it is hot out here!
就这个家伙 能是冒险游戏里的角色吗？
How is this guy a character in an adventure game?
好了 好了 好了
Okay, okay, okay.
我会继续塑造我的体型 提高一下持久力
I gotta get this guy in shape and build up some endurance.
我知道该怎么做
I know how to do that.
做波比跳 五个波比跳 马上做
Burpees. Five burpees, right now.
现在就开始！
Get it going!
-一个 -已经做了一个！
- That's one. - One!
-噢 不 -噢 你行的 再来！
- Oh, no. - Oh, yeah, come on!
那个方向是北方
North is that way!
你知道吗 嗯...
You know, it's, uh...
能见到你真好 埃迪
It's really good to see you, Ed.
我不想听
I don't wanna hear it.
难道你不想听到 见到你真好吗
You don't wanna hear that it's good to see you?
-你背叛了我 麦洛 -我没有背叛你
- You sold me out, Milo. - I did not sell you out.
我们卖了生意 是时候该退休了
We sold our business. It was time.
-谁该退休了？-嗯 当然是我们
- Yeah, time for who? - Well, it was time for me.
好吗？一直站着
Okay? Standing on my feet,
每晚端上上百个盘子 35年了
serving a hundred plates a night for 35 years?
我受够了
I was done.
我准备好了 哥们
I was ready, man.
我准备好了退休
I was ready to retire.
我懒得跟你说了
I'm done talking!
“绿洲到了”
"The Oasis."
我才那就是下一关了
I guess that's the next level.
啊？
Huh?
游戏的下一关
The next level of the game.
我们在游戏里吗？
We're in a game?
额 埃迪爷爷 我们在游戏里
Oh. Yes, Grandpa Eddie, we are in a game.
你肯定是在逗我
You can't be serious.
你知道这事吗
Did you know about this?
我以为你懒得跟我说了
I thought you were done talking.
-贝瑟妮？-是的
- Bethany? - Yep.
-我也叫贝瑟妮 -真的吗？
- My name's Bethany too. - Really?
爸爸 她也叫贝瑟妮
Daddy, her name's Bethany too.
没错 宝贝
Sure is, sweetie.
我可以跟你说几句话吗
Can I talk to you for a minute?
当然可以 进来吧
Sure, yeah. Uh, come in.
我很抱歉  我只是
I'm sorry, I just...
我不知道我还能找谁
I didn't know where else to go.
噢 不 没事的
No, no, no, it's okay.
我很高兴你能来
I'm glad you came.
你能不能帮我重新启动游戏机
Do you think you can help me get the machine to start?
那样做太危险了
That is so dangerous.
我知道
I know.
但我必须试一下
But I have to try.
他们是我的伙伴
They're my team.
对了 我们到底要找什么来着？
So, what exactly are we looking for again?
找我的外孙  天才
We're looking for my grandson, genius.
好了 跟着火焰找到沙漠之果
Okay, "Follow the flame to the desert fruit."
快看
Look.
他们在这里
They're here.
这是鬣狗
Hyenas.
特别之处在于那口能咬碎骨头的牙齿
Unusual for their bone-crushing teeth.
(烟囱酒吧)
烟囱酒馆
Smoke Stack.
有烟的地方
Where's there's smoke...
就有火焰
There's fire.
-走吧 -嗯
- Come on. - Mm.
-轰！-是你做的？
- Boom! - You call that a roll?
还不错嘛
Not bad at all.
我赌你还会输
I'll bet you two more!
喝酒！再喝一杯
Drinks! Drinks over here!
再来一轮！
Another round here!
-太棒了！-太棒了!
- Yeah! - Yeah!
我以为你不会再回来了
I thought you'd never come back.
我有话跟你说
I need to talk to you.
当然可以
Absolutely.
不能在这里 不是现在
Not here, not now.
不能在他们眼皮子底下
Not around them.
离我远点
Leave me alone!
噢
Wow.
真火辣
Fiery.
这不是真人
Not a real person.
-她说了什么？-她说她以为
- What'd she say? - Well, she said she thought
我不会回来了 想待会儿跟我见个面
I was never gonna come back, she wants to get together later,
-我想你们都懂这是什么意思 -哎呦
- and we all know what that means. - Hiyo!
意思是她有线索跟你交流
It means that she's got a clue for you.
那可真巧了 因为我也想跟她深入交流一下
Oh, that's a coincidence. I got a clue for her.
你想跟她深入交流一下 等等
- You got a clue for her. - Wait.
她是你前任女友 她就是火焰
She's your ex-girlfriend. She's the flame.
跟着火焰   什么？
- "Follow the flame." - What?
宝石  它在这里
The jewel, it's here.
等一下 就是那家伙杀了我父母吗？
Is that the guy that killed my parents?
不是   好吧  算是他吧
No. Well, yeah. Kind of.
我们今天失去了一名好手
We lost a good man today.
他是我们中最棒的
The very best of us.
因为戴格芬
For Dagfinn...
不仅是我的鬣狗训练师
wasn't just my hyena master.
也是我的朋友
He was my friend.
我拿他当兄弟
I loved him like a brother.
但现在他死了
And now he's gone.
扔下他心爱的鬣狗
And his beloved hyenas are left...
再也没有了训练师
without their master.
戴格芬万岁
Long live Dagfinn.
Long live Dagfinn!
他为什么必须死呢
Why did he have to die?
因为
He died because...
他犯了个错误
he made a mistake.
他想偷走我珍爱的一样东西
He tried to steal something quite precious from me.
所以我没得选
He left me no choice.
现在
And now...
我要用他来喂他心爱的鬣狗
I feed him to his beloved hyenas.
-真够恶心的  -噢！
- That's messed up. - Oh!
我爱戴格芬
I loved Dagfinn!
你们当中我最喜欢他了
There's none among you I love as much.
所以
And so...
钥匙
The key!
钥匙不见了
It's gone.
抓小偷
Thief!
抓住了  我抓住小偷了
I got her. I got the thief.
等等
Wait.
-你们是不是…   -过来
- Are you guys...? Wha...? - Come here.
-抓住她  -别让她跑了
- Catch her! - Don't let her get away.
你想偷我宝藏的钥匙吗
Trying to steal the key to my chest?
不
Nope.
给我搜
Shake her down.
对不起  是我偷的  我错了
I'm sorry, I did it. It was my fault.
我
I, uh...
我只是…  我
I just... I don't...
我不知道自己怎么了  老天
I don't know what I was... Oy vey.
我好像呼吸困难
Uh, it's like, um... It's like I'm hyperventilating.
你们谁有精油吸入器
Does anyone have, like, a eucalyptus inhaler?
或者棕色纸袋
Or a brown paper bag?
斯潘瑟
Spencer?
这里是不是太热了
Is it really hot in here?
你是说
You mean...?
-就是他  他就在这  -什么
- That's him. Right there. - What?
那不是斯潘瑟  听着  我认识我外孙
That ain't Spencer. Look, I know my grandson.
我外孙是男孩子
My grandson's a guy.
他是不是换发型了
Did he change his hair?
-砍了她的头  -对！
- Cut off her head. - Yeah!
-砍了她的头  -等等  等等
- Cut off her head! - Wait, wait, wait.
我只是想说  能别砍我的头吗
I just think, uh, maybe don't cut off my head?
-噢！  -斯潘瑟
- Oh! - Spencer!
-天哪  -他是不是
- Oh, my. - Did he just...?
噢天哪
Oh, Lord.
这是我的闹铃
That's my Life Alert.
我该吃药了
I gotta take my pill.
快点
Come on!
斯潘瑟
Spencer!
天哪  你还活着
Oh, my God, you're alive.
你们来这里干什么
What are you guys doing here?
我们来这干什么？  我们来救你  你个笨蛋
What are we doing here? We came to get you, fool!
-贝瑟尼  -不是贝瑟尼  老子是冰箱
- Bethany? - Not Bethany. Fridge, goddamn it!
什么  那么
What? So, um...
我是迈洛?沃克  亲爱的
Milo Walker, darling.
迈洛
Milo?
-斯潘瑟  是你吗  孩子  -外公
- Spencer? Is that you, kiddo? - Grandpa?
伙计们  我找到斯潘瑟了  就是她
Guys, I found Spencer. Here's Spencer right here.
你为什么要偷东西
What are you stealing for?
-我还是我  -噢
- I'm still me. - Oh.
嘿
Hey.
-嗨  -嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
快走
Come on.
我们走
Let's go.
该死  就差一点了  我都拿到钥匙了
Damn it, I was so close. I had the key in my hand.
-你为什么要拦住我  -哈？  有人喊抓小偷
- Why'd you stop me? - Huh? Someone yelled "thief,"
我就抓住你了  不然你想怎么样
so I grabbed you. What do you want?
你们不该来的  本来一切都在我的掌控中
You shouldn't have come. I had it under control.
是吗  貌似你刚刚才被人杀了
Did you? It looked like you just got murdered.
我说你搞什么  斯潘瑟  你怎么又进来了
I mean, what the hell, Spencer? Why are you even here?
你怎么会有游戏机
Why did you have the game?
我们毁了它  就是为了防止这种事再次发生
We destroyed it so that this would never happen!
我把它捡回来了  行吗
I went back and got it, okay?
我也不知道为什么这么做  但我就是做了
I don't know why I did it, but I did.
然后昨晚
And then last night...
我昨晚情绪不太对劲
I've been in kind of a weird place,
这个念头突然冒出来了
and something came over me, okay?
我们又一次被困在这里了
And now we're all stuck here again!
我以为我会变成他  变成勇者
I thought that I would be him. Bravestone!
我想重新找回那种感觉
I wanted to feel like that again.
就好像   我无所不能
Like... I could do anything.
但结果我成了  我
But instead, I'm, um...
女神偷阿明
Ming Fleetfoot.
飞檐走壁  扒窃  开保险箱
"Cat burglar, pickpocket, safecracker."
又一个厉害角色
Another better character.
-弱点  花粉  -没错
- "Weakness: pollen." - Yeah.
她个头小  人机灵  又有过敏症
She's small and crafty and has allergies.
基本上就是女版的我
She's basically me.
我发誓  要是我们能活下来
I swear, man, if we survive,
我要杀了你
I am gonna kill you.
我不敢相信你会主动回到这里
I just can't believe you came back here on purpose.
我很抱歉  行吗
I'm sorry. Okay?
对不起
I'm sorry.
等等
Wait!
噢她来了
Oh, there she is.
-谁  -我前任
- Who? - My ex.
好吧
Okay.
嗨
Hi.
如果我丈夫发现我和你说话的话
If my husband knew I was talking to you,
你活不过明天
you'd be dead by morning.
那别和他说
Uh, don't tell him?
听我说  尤尔根要带着他的人
Listen to me, Jurgen and his army
回到要塞
are returning to his fortress.
在那里  他会接见卡巴比克兄弟
There, they will meet the Brothers Kababik.
并把神鹰宝石卖给他们  双方缔结联盟
He will trade the Falcon Jewel, and an alliance will be formed.
你必须抢到那之前拿到宝石
You must get the jewel before that happens.
你是我们唯一的希望
You're our only hope,
所以一定要抓紧
so you must hurry.
天哪
Oh, my.
-你现在该走了  -该走了
- Now you must go. - Gotta go.
等等  他们要见什么兄弟
They're gonna meet the Brothers who?
卡巴比克兄弟
The Brothers Kababik.
-巴巴比克兄弟  -嘘
- The Brothers Bababik. - Shh!
-卡巴比克  -你必须要在那之前
- Kababik? - You must get the jewel
得到宝石
before that happens.
你是我们唯一的希望  所以你得抓紧
You are our only hope, so you must hurry.
我觉得你得再给我们解释一遍
I think you should explain it to us one more time.
-等一下  -噢
- Wait a second. - Oh!
沙漠之果怎么办
What about the desert fruit?
你不带我们去找吗
Aren't you gonna lead us to that?
我必须要走了
Now I must go...
趁弹簧刀还没发现我不见了
before Switchblade realizes I'm gone.
什么  弹簧刀
What? Switchblade?
那是他的弱点
That's his weakness.
我爱你  勇石博士
I love you, Dr. Bravestone.
我会永远爱你
And I always will.
而这
That...
是我的诅咒
is my curse.
我也爱你
I love you too!
她看起来不错
Well, she seems like a nice girl.
我们需要骆驼
We need camels.
好了各位  我们要想追上尤尔根  就得靠骆驼
Okay, if we're gonna catch up with Jurgen, we need camels.
还要找到那个沙漠之果什么的
And we need to find the desert fruit, whatever that is.
“跟着火焰”  我觉得我们得跟着她
"Follow the flame." I guess we have to follow her.
你们跟着她  我们去偷几匹骆驼
You guys follow her, we'll go steal some camels.
哇哦
Whoa.
尤曼吉果树
"Jumanji Berry Tree."
尤曼吉果
Jumanji berry?
是沙漠之果吗
That's a desert fruit?
我猜是的
I guess.
需要之时  想想果实
"In the moment of need, remember the seed."
尤曼吉的智慧格言
A little bit of Jumanji wisdom there.
它在那
There it is.
我和迈洛进去偷骆驼
Milo and I will break in and get the camels.
外公 你在这里望风 好吗
Grandpa, you stay here on lookout. Keep a low profile.
低调一点 懂吗
Got it? Low profile.
要是有人想进去
If anyone tries to enter the livery,
我也不知道 你就吹个口哨之类的
just, I don't know, whistle or something.
没问题
Sure thing.
这时候不用眼神杀
That's not when you smolder.
现在不是时候 别在意
It's not the moment for it. Forget it.
这是自然反应 我都不知道是怎么回事
I did it. I don't know what it was.
你那样子像是肚子疼
Look like your stomach is upset.
好像吃了什么脏东西
Like you ate something bad.
天啊
Oh, man.
我在冒汗 我在冒汗
I'm sweating. I'm sweating.
偷东西真叫我心里不舒服
Stealing makes me very uncomfortable,
这可不好 我是个神偷
which is not ideal for a burglar.
果实在树上
So the fruit is in the tree.
要想拿到果实
But you can't get to it
我们必须下水
without going through the water
不管这是不是水
or whatever that is.
要么被煮熟 要么被食人鱼或别的东西吃掉
Get boiled or eaten by piranhas or something.
跟着火焰
"Follow the flame."
我觉得这就是过去的办法
I think that's how we get there.
可我不知道怎么才能跳过去
But I don't know how I'm supposed to make that jump.
这办法虽然可行 但是
I mean, it's doable...
我可没有平时的爆发力
but I don't have my usual explosiveness.
-啊  -哦吼
- Ugh! - Wh... Ho! Yo!
哟吼
Ho, ho, ho! Wow!
干得好
Yes!
玛莎
Martha! Ho!
Martha!
哦
Oh...
玛莎 哦 这东西沉死了
- Martha! - Oh, it's really heavy.
你没事吧  把手给我
Ugh! You okay? Give me your hand.
上来
There you go.
哦
Ow. Oh...
等一下
Wait a second.
什么  天啊
- What...? - The hell, man?
我的天
Oh, my God!
开什么玩笑
- The hell, man? - Oh, my God.
冰箱 是的
- Fridge? - Yeah.
玛莎
Martha?
是的
Yeah.
一边去 没什么好看的
Hey, move along. Nothing to see here.
你说什么
What'd you say?
我说 走你的路 伙计
I said, keep walking, pal.
没什么好看的 滚开
Nothing to see here. Beat it.
你说什么 我说滚开 闪一边去
- What'd you say? - Beat it, get out of here.
你说什么
What'd you say?
我说滚一边去
I said, scram!
想跟我打一架吗 来啊 来啊 吃我一拳
You want a piece of me? Yeah, come on, come on.
你们有什么本事  什么本事
What do you got? What do you got? Come on!
来啊
Come and get it. Yeah!
放马过来 一群混蛋
Come on, you bastards!
哈哈哈
Ha, wow! Ha, ha!
来呀  骆驼 骆驼
Here, camel, camel.
来呀 跟我走
Come on, let's go.
它们真是骄傲而威严的动物 是不是
They are proud and majestic animals, aren't they?
不用客气
Oh, you're welcome. Heh.
你是不是 你刚才在跟它们说话吗
Did you...? Were you just talking to them?
按菜单键  我在这里
Um, press your menu. Uh, it's right here.
语言学
"Linguistics."
你能跟动物交流
You can talk to animals.
是的
Yes.
看起来我会说骆驼语
It appears that I speak camel.
能不能它们跟我们一起走
Can you ask them to come with us and...?
不好意思
Excuse me.
它们愿意谈谈
They're willing to talk.
他们想知道得到什么好处
Uh, they wanna know what's in it for them
以及我们有多少行李
and how much luggage we have.
见了鬼了
Will you look at me? Oh!
我说 角色能干什么
I mean, what am I supposed to do with this?
你能看地图
You read the map.
我不想看地图 我应该是她才对
I don't wanna read the map. I'm supposed to be her.
而且我脸上竟然还长毛了
Instead, there's actual hair growing out of my face!
抱歉 所有的身体都美 甚至包括这个
Sorry. All bodies are beautiful, even this one.
先等一下
Wait a second.
感觉太棒了  你小心点
- Oh, this is amazing! - Careful.
冰箱
Fridge...
这个角色太牛了
Yo, this thing is insane!
小心点 那具身体可不是玩具
Be careful. That body is not a toy.
对 它是一台机器
No, it's a machine.
最重要的是
And on top of that...
有胸
boobs.
你敢碰我的胸 我就弄死你
Touch my boobs, and I will murder you.
太晚了 我一反应过来就摸了
Too late. It was literally the first thing I did.
哟
Ew!
嗨 别这样
Hey, hey, don't do that.
我们拿上尤曼吉果 跟他们会合
Let's take this berry and go meet them.
别急嘛 姑娘
Relax, girl.
我要像你那样玩杂技飞过去
I'm trying that flying acrobat thing you did.
不要 我们拿到果实了 看好了
- Don't. We have the berry. - Check this out.
你没必要这样 做好准备
- It's not necessary. - Omaha, Omaha!
上 上 等等
- Hut, hut, hike! - Wait.
冰箱 小心点 我告诉你 那具身体是人形兵器
Fridge, be careful! I am telling you, that body's a weapon.
你都不知道它的能力有多大
You don't know what it's capable of.
感觉太棒了
This is amazing!
那具身体是上了膛的枪
That body's a loaded gun!
对 现在这把枪要开火了
Yeah! And this gun's about to go off!
喔 哦
Whoo... Oh!
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
冰箱
Fridge!
过来 啊
- Come here. - Ugh!
真是该死
Oh, my God. Goddamn it!
把手给我
- Here, I got you. I got ya. - Ugh!
哦 不 不是吧
Oh, no. Oh, no. Oh, no!
我的天 刚才吓死我了
Oh, my God, that was awful.
我不想当看地图的
I hate being the map guy!
我们离开这里
Let's get out of here.
弹簧刀 他在那里
Switchblade! There he is.
勇石
Bravestone!
我说了让你离我老婆远一点
I told you to stay the hell away from my wife!
有人过来了 你做了什么
- We got company. - What did you do?
好了朋友们 时候到了 我们现在需要你们
All right, guys, this is the moment. We need you now.
它们说我们可以从后门出去
Uh, they said that we can get away out the back door.
你在跟骆驼讲话吗 是的
- Are you talking to that camel? - Yes.
这是露西尔 那是汉克
That's Lucille and Hank.
后面的是杰弗里
And Jeffrey's in the back.
嘿
- Hey! - Hey.
我们得走了 发生了什么
- We should get going. - What happened?
我外公无缘无故地揍了25个陌生人
My grandpa beat up 45 strangers.
现在那个女生的丈夫要杀了他
That woman's husband is trying to kill him.
呃
Mm.
那是沙漠之果吗
Is that the desert fruit?
是的 它叫尤曼吉果
Yeah. It's a Jumanji berry,
这玩意有一百磅那么重
and it weighs like 100 pounds.
让我外公拿着
My grandpa will carry it.
我们赶紧离开这里
We should get out of here.
走了 外公 快走
Come on, Grandpa. Let's go.
我能解决他们 什么
- I could take them. - What?
你说什么呢 我们都逃掉了
What? We escaped.
我说我能解决他们 噢 埃迪
- I said, I could take them. - Oh, Eddie.
不行 埃迪爷爷 那可是弹簧刀
No, Grandpa Eddie, that's Switchblade!
我跟你说 人生中有些时候你可以逃跑
I'm telling you, there's a time when you run.
但像现在这种时候 你得留下
Then there's a time in life, like now, where you stay...
好啊 好啊
Yeah! Yeah!
弹簧刀 弹簧刀
Switchblade! Switchblade!
准头真好 弹簧刀
Nice shot, Switchblade!
哦
- Oh! - Phew.
干什么
What?
我们应该离扎特迈尔山不远了
We should see Mount Zhatmire pretty soon.
我和葛兰迪之前一起旅行过 在她去世前
You know, Gladys and I took a road trip before she passed.
进行着一场陶瓷之路
We went on a ceramics tour
穿越西南
through the Southwest.
我丢了我的餐馆 所以你可以开车到处走
I lost my restaurant so you could drive around
去看烟灰缸 是的
- and look at ashtrays? - Yes, Ed.
这就是你退休后做的事
That's what you do when you retire.
你发现了你的兴趣所在
You explore your interests.
我没有兴趣爱好
I don't have interests.
像我这样的人 绝不退休
Guys like me, we don't retire!
我们工作 然后我们不停地工作
We work, and then we keep working,
最终 死去
and then, eventually, we die.
但是你让我退休了  是你让我退休了
-But you retired me. -You retired me.
我坚持与你共事这么久真是奇迹
It's a wonder I lasted as long as I did.
什么？ 你是个难相处的人 埃德
- What? - You're a difficult man, Ed.
你不能抛弃你最好的朋友 迈洛
You don't abandon your best friend, Milo.
我失去餐厅意味着我什么都没了
When I lost the restaurant, I lost everything!
你？
You...?
是 是的 我知道他确实是
Yes. Yes, I know he is.
你在和骆驼讲话吗？  是的 我在和骆驼讲话
- Are you talking to my camel? - Yes, I'm talking to the camel.
并且它知道你是个讨厌鬼
And he can tell that you're a pain in the ass.
我的骆驼站在你那边？
My camel's taking your side?
它并不是你的骆驼
And he's not your camel.
它只是驼你一程
He's just giving you a ride.
好啊 那你们俩一起见鬼去吧
Oh! Well, how about the both of you go screw yourselves?
你刚才说什么？ 朋友们！
- What did you just say? - Guys!
你和我 我们就现在 在这里把话说清楚
You and me, we gonna settle this right here, right now!
我要跟你说清楚  你在干什么？
- I'll show you. - What are you doing?
别担心  迈洛 你在干什么？
- Don't worry about it. - Milo, what are you doing?
等等 等等 开始
Hold on. Wait, wait. Here we go.
你要打我一顿吗 啊？这就是你想要的？
You want a piece of me, huh? That's what you want?
你并不真的想打他 迈洛 我告诉你
You do not want a piece of him, Milo, I'm telling you.
哦 那你就错了 年轻人
Oh, that's where you're wrong, young man.
因为我就是想打他一顿
'Cause I do want a piece.
我想和他大打一架
I want a big piece.
告诉你 埃迪 你不知道的是 过去15年
See, Eddie, what you don't know is that for the last 15 years,
我一直都在学太极
I've been studying tai chi.
现在
And right now,
我正在运气
I am harnessing my chi.
当我准备好了 我就要把你打趴
And when I'm done, I'm gonna whup your ass.
迈洛 听我依据 这并不是个好事
Milo, I am telling you, this is not a good idea.
不
No!
哦 兄弟
Oh, dude!
你可别再杀生了
You gotta stop killing everybody.
好吧 那么
All right, then.
我觉得我们的事解决了
Well, I guess that's settled.
骆驼不走了
The camels just stopped.
它们只能走这么远了
This is as far as they go.
要想去尤尔根要塞 他们说我们可以
To get to Jurgen's fortress, they said that we can
沿着这条路走然后右转
head down this path here and make a right.
我们就能到他们的地盘了
Then we're in his territory.
它们不想过去
And they don't wanna go there
是因为它们不想死
because they don't want to die.
我们也不想死
We don't wanna die either.
没见过这么糟糕的勇石
He's the worst Bravestone of all time.
那么我们要穿过...这个了
So we have to get across... this.
行 我们可以的 我们可以的
Okay, we can do this. We can do this.
我们要花点时间 做一个慎重的觉得
We have to take our time, make careful decisions.
你在说什么？这不是很明显
What are you talking about? It's obvious.
我们先上这座桥
We start on that bridge there,
然后跳到那一座 再向右走
then jump to that one that heads to the right about 30 degrees,
然后到两边呈梯形的...
and then those look like two sides of a trapezoid...
几何学 派上用场了
Geometry. That's what it's for!
也许我这个角色也不是完全没用
Maybe this character's not totally worthless.
我先来  真的吗？
- I'll go first. - Really?
看到了吗？没什么大不了的
You see? It's no big deal.
哦 这怎么了？
Oh. What's going on?
哦 不 不 不   哦 不
- Oh, no, no, no. - Oh, no.
外公！
- No. - Grandpa!
哦 见鬼
Ah, crap.
哦 天啊
Ah, geez.
这是什么鬼？
What the hell?
看来没事 我们可以做到  真的吗？
- It's okay. We can do this. - Yeah?
重点是找准时机
It's about finding the right timing.
快来 快来 快来  跟上我
- Come on, come on, come on. - Follow me.
快过来
Come on!
快来 迈洛 快来！
Come on, Milo, come on!
啊！哦！哦！
Ah! Whoa! Whoa!
哦！天啊  这里
- Oh! Oh, Lord. - Here.
好的
Oh, okay.
喂 朋友们
Hey, you guys.
那个石头...在动吗？
Is that rock... moving?
完了  什么?
- Oh, no. - What?
我们遇到大麻烦了
Well, now, this is a problem.
快说 到底怎么了？ 天啊
- Come on, what is it? - Oh, my.
赶紧说！ 这是什么？
- Spit it out! - What is it?
说啊！ 快说！迈洛！
- Tell us! - Tell us! Milo!
他们是山魈
Those are mandrills.
我们要马上离开 走 走！ 走！
- We should go. Go, go! - Go!
上那座桥！成钝角的那座！
That one! Obtuse angle!
看他们脸上和屁股上
Note the distinctive and colorful pigment
明显的彩色颜料
around their face and buttocks.
山魈是所有猴子中块头最大的一种
Mandrills are the heaviest of all monkeys.
甚至比狒狒还大 以至于它们经常被混淆
Even heavier than baboons, with which they are often confused.
现在去菱形那座桥
And now head for the rhombus!
快来 赶紧的
Come on. Hurry up.
菱形 菱形的    快来
- Rhombus! Rhombus! - Come on.
不对 玛莎
No, Martha!
你上错桥了！  什么？
- You're on the wrong bridge! - What?
跟这座桥垂直的那座
The perpendicular one!
玛莎！
Martha!
不！
No!
斯潘瑟 小心后面！
Spencer, behind you!
跳！
Jump!
快点 我接着你！
Come on, I got you!
斯潘瑟！
Spencer!
Oh, 不! Ow! Ow!
Oh, no! Ow! Ow!
哦！不！不！啊！啊！
Oh, no! No! Ow! Ow!
滚开！
Get off!
过来
Come on.
好吧 放马过来
All right, bring it on.
过来 到这来 哈！哈！
Come on, come here. Ha, ha!
外公！ 啊！
- Grandpa! - Ow!
外公！够了！
Grandpa! Enough!
外公 停下来！ 好的！
- Grandpa, stop! - Yeah!
他们都走了！
They're gone!
哦！ 好！
- Whoa! - Yeah!
快走！
Come on!
收给我
Give me your hand!
什么？ 相信我！
- What? - Trust me!
哦！走
Oh! Go.
最后一座桥 瞄准抛物线中间
Last one. Aim for the center of the parabola!
哦 见鬼！
Oh, damn. Ugh! Son of a...
哦！
Ow!
噢！噢！噢！
Oh! Oh! Oh!
埃迪？ 迈洛！
- Eddie? - Milo!
埃迪！喂 埃迪 你去哪里？
Eddie! Hey, Eddie, where you going?
我需要你帮忙 埃迪
I need your help, Eddie.
埃迪！
Eddie!
哦！
Oh!
哦！ 啊
- Oh! - Ugh.
埃迪！迈洛！
Eddie! Milo!
哦！
Oh!
开玩笑的吧？等等
- Seriously? - Later.
快跑！快跑！
- Run! - Run!
吁！
Hyah!
嗨 你们好
Hey, guys.
这是谁？
Who the hell's this?
艾利克斯 你来这里做什么？
Alex, what are you doing here?
贝瑟妮认为你们可能需要帮助
Bethany thought you might need some help.
贝瑟妮在哪里？  她就在这里
- Where is Bethany? - She's right here.
你是说...？
You mean...?
真不可思议 是吗？
"Oh, my God, right?
我简直就是一匹马
Like, I'm a total horse.
我没想到我们竟然找到了你们
I can't believe that we found you guys.
嗨
Hi."
对的 它是贝瑟妮. 哈哈哈 怎么了 美女？
Yep, that's Bethany. Ha-ha-ha. What's up, girl?
你好啊
Hey.
哦 我们给你们带了些衣服
Oh, we brought you some clothes.
你们肯定冻坏了
You must be freezing.
那么 这匹马是游戏中的一个角色？
So, uh, this horse is a character in the game?
是的 它叫旋风
Yeah. Cyclone's his name.
感觉如何？ 我不知道
- How's that feel? - I don't know.
我崴得有些严重
I sprained it pretty good.
你们在哪里弄的这些衣服？
Where'd you get these clothes?
当我意识到我们要往北走多远
When I realized how far north we were going,
我们就停下来去买了写东西  哦
- we stopped to go shopping. - Ah.
你还能在这里买到东西？你怎么知道的？
You can shop here? How did you know that?
我在这里呆了20年了 小朋友
I was here for 20 years, kiddo.
至少我摆脱了那顶愚蠢的帽子
At least I got rid of that stupid hat.
结果换了顶更蠢的
Now I got this stupid hat.
这景色很了不起 不是吗？
It's something, isn't it?
是的 很壮观
Yeah, it's something.
你知道吗 埃迪..
You know, Eddie...
你失去餐厅的时候并不代表你失去了一切
you didn't lose everything when you lost the restaurant.
你还有很多东西呢 兄弟
You still got a lot, man.
我失去了我的挚友
I lost my friend.
我也是
So did I.
对不起 迈洛
I'm sorry, Milo.
我也应该说抱歉 埃迪
Hey, I'm sorry too, Eddie.
我应该早点回去跟你和好
I should have tracked you down a long time ago.
我很高兴你过来喝咖啡
I'm glad you came over for coffee.
为什么你会回来找我
What made you do it, huh?
我是说 为什么是现在？
I mean, why now?
迈洛 出了什么事？
Milo, what's going on?
你病了
You're sick.
有多严重？
How bad?
我活不了几天了
I don't have much time left.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
但我觉得自己很幸运 埃迪
But I count myself lucky, Eddie.
我娶了一个很棒的女人
I was married to a wonderful woman.
度过了精彩的一生
I got to live a wonderful life.
并不是每个人都敢说这话
And not everybody can say that.
这就是为什么我想和你重归于好
That's why I wanted to make things better with you.
现在我们和好了
And now that they are...
我..
well, I'm...
我也就开心了
I'm happy about that too.
爷爷 迈洛 快点 我们得走了
Grandpa, Milo. Come on, we gotta go.
“堡垒 ”
"The Fortress."
看起来像是最后一关
Looks like the last level.
好吧 我们爬上那座山
Okay, so we, uh, climb that mountain
然后我们再想办法偷偷溜进去
and then we sneak in somehow.
是的 然后我们把宝石偷到手
Yeah, and then we steal the jewel
在卡巴比克兄弟 到达之前
before the Brothers Kababik get there.
- 然后让它沐浴阳光吗?  -听起来像个计划
- And then show it to the sun? - Sounds like a plan.
什么
What?
对不起 我想我没听出这个计划是什么计划
I'm sorry, I think I missed the "plan" part of the plan.
上一关 我们差点全军覆没 我几乎没法走路
That last level almost killed us all. I can barely walk.
如果你爷爷又胡乱打死人
Your grandpa beats the hell out of the wrong guy
或者我们撞上北极熊什么的 我该怎么办
or we get attacked by a bear, what am I supposed to do?
我不会胡乱打死人的
I'm not gonna beat up the wrong guy.
一定会胡乱打死人的
You are gonna beat up the wrong guy!
你不配当一个勇者
You're not a good Bravestone!
你这人太固执 太暴躁
You're too stubborn and pissed off.
还一直在坑队友
You keep getting us killed.
你在胡说什么
What the hell you talking about?
还有迈洛..
And Milo...
恕我直言 先生
And I say this with all due respect, sir.
不适合做动物学家
...is not a good person to be the zoologist.
他说话太慢了 到那时
He talks too slow, and by the time
等他说到重点的时候 人都死了！
he gets to the point, you're dead!
再说一次 无意冒犯
Once again, no offense.
没关系
None taken.
让我告诉你原因
And let me tell you why.
- 因为我的朋友伯纳德...  -看到了吗？
- Because my friend Bernard... - You see?
你这个贼偷东西都战战兢兢的
You're a thief who's too neurotic to steal,
贝瑟妮变成了一匹马
Bethany's a horse...
我只知道我们又被困在这里了,
All I know is, we are stuck here again,
我们快没命了 我的脚踝疼死了! 啊！
we are running out of lives, and my ankle is killing me! Ahh!
- 天啊!  -冰箱！
- Oh, my God! - Fridge!
冰箱! 你没事吧？
Fridge! Are you okay?
你们得来看看这个！
Yo, you guys gotta see this!
这跟那棵树下的池水一样
That's what the water looked like at the tree.
当时我们..
When we...
互换了身体
Switched bodies.
- 该死 太冷了!  -哦！
- Goddamn, that is cold! - Oh!
哦! 哦 伙计! 太冷了！
Oh! Oh, man! It's freezing!
搞什么 伙计？
What the hell, man?
太好了！
Yes!
我想死你了
I missed you so much.
天啊 大家好
Oh, my God, you guys, hi.
嗯 斯潘瑟？
Ahem, Spencer?
- 嘿-嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
-爷爷?  -是我 怎么了？
- Grandpa? - Yeah, what?
迈洛？
Milo?
你应该看看你的尺寸
You should see the size of your...
该死
Phew. Damn.
没想到我还有乐意当小矮子的一天
I never thought I'd be this happy to shrink.
我从来没见过那种场面
I have never seen anything quite like that before.
哦 天哪 太好了
Oh, my God, it's so good
我又可以说人话了
to be able to talk again with words.
- 斯潘瑟 嗨   -嘿 贝瑟妮
- Spencer, hi! - Hey, Bethany.
我们还有很多要聊的
We have so much catching up to do.
我想听你说说纽约的事
I wanna hear about New York.
但是感觉现在不是时候
But it feels like this isn't the perfect moment.
好吧 以后再聊
Right. Like, later.
以后再聊
Later.
- 好点了吗?  -是的
- Better? - Yeah.
好多了
Much.
我长头发了
I got hair! Heh, heh!
40年来第一次 我得去告诉迈洛
For the first time in 40 years. I gotta go tell Milo.
- 小心点 爷爷  -好的
- Be careful out there, Grandpa. - Yeah.
- 你的脚踝怎么样了? -嗯？
- How's your ankle? - Hm?
- 你的脚踝   -有点疼
- Your ankle. - It's a little sore.
不过绝对没有你表现得那么严重
Not as bad as you were making it seem.
- 你这话什么意思?  -没什么
- What's that supposed to mean? - Nothing.
你小题大做了 没那么糟糕
You were making a big deal of it. It's not that bad.
嘿! 离那匹马远点！
Hey! Get the hell away from that horse!
不许动！
Freeze!
迈洛! 嘿！
Milo! Hey!
等等 是哪个脚踝崴了来着？
Wait, which ankle was it?
- 等等  -嘿嘿嘿
- Hold it. - Hey, hey, hey.
放开我！
Get your hands off of me!
我就在你身边 迈洛
Hey! I'm with you, Milo.
我就在这儿
I'm right here.
伙计们伙计们
Guys, guys.
埃迪和迈洛
Eddie and Milo.
被抓走了
They got them.
山上到处都是冰,
There's ice everywhere,
只有一条路可以进去
and there's only one road in.
到处都是守卫 我不知道我们怎么进去
It's covered with guards. I don't know how we'll get in.
哇！
Hm. Whoa!
好吧 我看到了一个地牢
Oh, okay. I see a dungeon
在这个冰墙的顶端
at the top of this ice wall.
他们一定把你爷爷关在那里
That must be where they're keeping your grandpa.
迈洛可能被关在主楼另一侧
And Milo is probably in this, like, barn thing
像个马厩的地方
all the way on the other side of the place.
好吧 我们得分头行动
Okay. We gotta split up.
一队去救迈洛 另一队去救爷爷
One team goes to get Milo, the other busts out Grandpa.
但我们怎么进去呢？
But how do we get in?
冰箱 你背包里
Fridge, do you have
有攀冰设备吗？
any ice-climbing equipment in your backpack?
你是说像这样的吗？
You mean something like this?
- 就是这个  -看到了吗？
- Just like that. - See?
所以我才是负责背包的人
That's why I'm the backpack guy.
- 这就是原因  -是啊 你很擅长这个
- That's why. - Yeah. You're great at that.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
玛莎 愿意跟我一起去吗？
Martha, will you come with me?
当然
Of course.
我差点忘了这种感觉
I forgot what this part feels like.
太可怕了
It's scary.
- 是啊 -嘿
- Yeah. - Hey.
我们能做到 这支队伍无所不能
We can do it. This team can do anything.
没有人比我更清楚这一点
Nobody knows that better than me.
- 是啊 -来吧伙计们
- Yeah. - Come on, you guys.
手靠过来
Bring it in.
一往无前
Be aggressive.
Be, be aggressive.
一往无前
Be aggressive.
一往无前  来吧 伙计们
Be, be aggressive. Come on, guys.
这场面跟我想的可不一样
That's not what I thought this was. No.
我们还是出发吧
We should just go.
好了... 上吧伙计们
Okay, just... Go, team.
好吧
Okay.
我要混进人群里溜进去
I'm gonna try to sneak in with them.
穿着这身衣服应该能蒙混过关 你们留在这里
In this outfit, I might be able to pass. You guys stay here...
什么? 不可能
What? No way.
时机到了 待在这里
Now's the moment. Stay here.
- 亚历克斯 不!  -去吧 祝你好运 亚历克斯
- Alex, no! - Go. Good luck, Alex.
来吧
Come on.
- 你在说什么”来吧” ?  -贝瑟妮
What are you talking about, "Come on"? Bethany.
贝瑟妮
Bethany!
右转
Turn right.
你们两个 站着别动
You there. Stay where you are.
谁 我们？
Who, us?
你们是卡巴比克兄弟吗？
Are you the Brothers Kababik?
- 什么兄弟?  -你们是卡巴比克兄弟吗？
- Are we the who? - Are you the Brothers Kababik?
是的
Yes.
是的 是我们 是我们
We are them. It is we. Us.
我们是卡达布拉兄弟... 卡达布里克兄弟
We are the Brothers Cadabra... Kadabrik.
他是两兄弟之一
He is one brother,
而我是另一个兄弟
and I am the other brother.
我们... 我们同父异母
We... We got different mothers.
我们来这里是想拿到我们该拿的东西的
But we, uh... We came to get the thing that we came to get.
卡巴比克兄弟,
Brothers Kababik,
我代表暴君尤尔根,
on behalf of Jurgen the Brutal,
欢迎你们来到扎特迈尔要塞
welcome to Zhatmire Stronghold.
谢谢
Ah, thank you.
有些事我必须问你
There's something I have to ask you.
好吧
Okay.
你为什么没来看我 我们本来说好的
Why didn't you come visit when you were supposed to?
第一次你放我鸽子
You canceled the first time,
然后万圣节那天你说会来 可你又放我鸽子
then you were gonna come for Halloween. You cancel again.
等到下次我再接到你的电话
Then the next time I hear from you,
你跟我说 我们应该冷静一下
you tell me we should take a break?
只是... 我看了你上传到INS的所有照片
It's just... I saw all your pictures on Instagram,
你看起来很开心
and you looked like you were having so much fun, and...
我只是觉得很没安全感
I just got really insecure or something.
觉得我没有自己想象的那么好
Like I wasn't the guy I thought I was.
我也没有你想得那么好
Or I wasn't the guy you thought I was.
这让我感觉更糟
Which would be even worse.
斯潘瑟 难道你以为
Spencer, do you think I'm not...
我就不是一直担惊受怕吗
totally terrified all the time?
我考上了大学
I got to school, and suddenly,
然后突然间 我第一次发现自己很受欢迎
for the first time ever, people really liked me.
但我一直在想..
But I'm always thinking that...
我也说不好 我就是觉得
I don't know, like it's...
迟早会有人
Like it's just a matter of time
看穿我的本质
before somebody figures out who I really am.
但后来我遇到了你
But then I see you.
你是那个让我感觉
And you're the person who makes me feel good...
做真实的自己也很好的人
about who I really am.
当你感到害怕和不安的时候,
When you're, like, scared and insecure,
那就更需要爱你的人来陪伴
that's when you need your people the most.
沃克先生
Hey, Mr. Walker.
为什么拉长着脸？
Why the long face?
哄孩子的玩笑 对不起 说习惯了
Dad joke. Sorry. Can't help it.
我带你离开这里
Let's get you out of here.
好吧
Okay.
这只是一个障碍挑战赛
It's just an obstacle course.
你很擅长这些
You were good at those.
好吧 好吧 要不你们去开个房间吧
All right, all right, get a room.
爷爷... 我们救你出来
Grandpa... let's get you out of there.
好吧
Here.
-啊! -哇
- Unh! - Whoa.
我们离开这个鬼地方吧 好吗？
Let's blow this joint, huh?
我们还得找到宝石呢
We still have to find the jewel.
它一定是在金库或者藏宝室之类的地方
It must be in a vault or treasure room or something.
是的 这就是游戏的套路
Yeah, that's how it works in these games.
我上来的时候路过了一个金库
I passed a vault on the way up to this dump.
就一个入口 3英尺厚的钢门
Single access, 3-foot-thick steel door.
只有通过天花板上的天窗才能进去
Only way in is through a grate in the ceiling.
呼... 哦
Hoo... Oh. Huh.
我想我弄明白了
I think I got it now.
我只需要踩在
Just stay on...
那些凸起的石头上
the raised ones.
暴君尤尔根在等着我们
Jurgen the Brutal awaits.
那么 告诉我 你们两兄弟 谁是谁
So, tell me, which brother is which?
你什么意思？
Um, how do you mean?
你们两兄弟 谁是谁
Which brother is which?
你们中间哪一个是奥古斯图斯 哪一个是托马托利？
Which of you is Augustus and which is Tomatoli?
我是奥古斯图斯
Um... I am Augustus.
我是托马托利
And I'm Tomatolik.
奥古斯图斯·卡巴比克
Augustus Kababik.
尤曼吉最聪明的人
The cleverest man in all of Jumanji.
说的就是我
Yes, I'm totally that man.
- 还有 托马托利·卡巴比克-就是我
- And Tomatoli Kababik. - That's me.
最勇敢的太监
The bravest eunuch.
- 等等 什么?  -你刚才是说”太监”吗？
- Wait a minute, what? - Did you say, "Eunuch"?
托马托利 · 卡巴比克 每个人都知道这个故事
Tomatoli Kababik, everyone knows the tale
你们伟大而无私的牺牲
of your great and generous sacrifice.
你牺牲了自己的睾丸
How you gave your testicles
让这个国家免受洪水的侵袭
in order to save the region from the floods.
我觉得这件事可能会有一点误会
There might be a little confusion.
当然 大家都知道我弟弟
Of course. Everybody knows the story
和他命根子的故事
about my little brother and his famous testicles.
- 无论它身在何方  -无论它身在何方
- Wherever they may be. - Wherever they may be.
好吧 话先说回来
All right, let's back up. Let's go back a little bit.
- 让我们澄清一些事情  -他超级勇敢
- Let's clear some stuff up. - He's super brave.
我一直都是超级聪明的,
I've always been the super clever one,
而他一直都很勇敢
and he's always been super brave.
- 而且超级没种 -别这么说！
- And super ball-less. - Stop saying that!
- 我的两个蛋蛋依旧健在!  -在你心里
- Both of my balls are right here! - In spirit.
- 嘿... -它就在你心里
- Hey... - They're here in spirit.
永远都在
Always.
肯定的
Of course.
对吧 兄弟？
Right, bro?
对
Right.
我是个没种的太监
I got no balls.
那里有个宝箱
There's the chest.
好了 该你出马了 爷爷
Okay. You're up, Grandpa.
- 谁 我?  -对 你就是那个飞贼
- Who, me? - Yes. You're the cat burglar.
- 嗯?  -你的角色 阿明
- Huh? - Your character, Ming.
-阿明  -对 阿明
- Ming? - Yes, Ming.
你这个角色的名字
Your avatar. That's her name.
在你的书包里 你有开锁器
In your satchel, you have lockpicks.
开锁工具? 我怎么会有开锁工具？
Lockpicks? Why would I have lockpicks?
因为阿明就是飞贼
Because Ming's the cat burglar.
你们不觉得应该你们上吗
Don't you think one of you should do this?
- 你有这能力  -我有能力吗？
- You have the skills. - I have the skills?
不是你 是阿明
Not you. Ming.
懂了 阿明
Right. Ming.
请不要问阿明是谁
Please don't ask who Ming is.
不错吧？
Not bad, huh?
现在我们得想办法怎么把你弄出去
Now we just gotta figure out how to get you out of here.
走吧？
Shall we?
哈
Huh.
这很酷
Now, that's cool.
欢迎 我可以请你吃一块蛋糕吗？
Welcome. May I offer you a piece of cake?
不! 不！
No! No!
不！
No!
不用了 谢谢
No, thank you.
稳住
Steady.
哈! 真该换那个叫阿明的下来
Ha! I'd like to see your friend Ming do that!
我们有麻烦了
We got an issue here.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
卡巴比克兄弟 这位是暴君尤尔根
Brothers Kababik, I present Jurgen the Brutal.
我们终于见面了
At last,
今天是历史性的一天
we meet on this historic day.
是的 很荣幸见到你
Yes, it is so great to meet you.
阁下 如果神鹰宝石
Your Honor, if that be the Falcon Jewel
就是您那五大三粗的脖子上挂着的那块
upon your thick and meaty neck,
也许您应该..
perhaps we should...
交给我们
take it.
今天 我们缔结了一个牢不可破的联盟
Today we forge an unbreakable alliance.
你们家族加入我的麾下
Your family will join me,
一起打拼天下 统治这个世界
and land by land, we'll take the world.
在这历史性的一天 我想问问
So I ask, on this historic day,
她在哪里
where is she?
- 你说的是谁? -你在说谁？
- Uh, where's who? - Who you talking about?
你妹妹
Your sister.
她很快就是我的新娘了
Soon to be my bride.
你知道吗? 我觉得这里面有什么误会
You know what? I think that there's been a misunderstanding.
你妹妹在哪儿？
Where is your sister?
你说的是哪个妹妹？
Which sister were we talking about?
黛比还是布鲁克？
Debbie or... Brooke?
还者 西耶拉？
Or Sierra?
你妹妹在哪儿？
Where is your sister?
她准备出嫁呢 就在旅馆里
She's getting ready, back at the hotel.
做一些出嫁当天要做的事
She's doing what brides do on their wedding day.
和闺蜜们在一起 做头发 做美甲
Hanging with the girls, getting her hair done, mani-pedi.
如果你没带你妹妹一起来这里..
If you come here without your sister...
那我只能砍掉你们的头了
I just might have to cut off your heads.
哦 不！ 不不不  不要  嘿  嘿  嘿！
- Oh, no! No, no, no. Don't. - Hey. Hey. Hey!
- 上帝 不  -嘿 放开我！
- God, no. - Hey, get off!
- 不要   -那我最后问你一次:
- No. No. - So I'll ask one last time:
你妹妹在哪儿？
Where is your sister?
我就在这儿
I'm right here.
格温多林 · 霍滕西亚 · 卢韦尔达 · 卡巴比克？
Gwendolyn Hortencia Lewelda Kababik?
是你吗？
Is that you?
是的
Um, yes.
就是我
That is me.
现在拜托您,
Now, please,
暴君阁下 请放了我的哥哥们
O Brutal One, release my brothers.
你是否愿意在这一天,
And is it your intention, on this day,
在这个时候 要嫁给扎特迈尔山的暴君尤尔根？
at this hour, to wed Jurgen the Brutal of Zhatmire?
没错 我就是这个想法
Yep. That's my plan.
你是否愿意为他生儿育女
And is it your intention to mother his children
与你的家族血脉相连 融为一体？
and forge in blood this union with your family?
是的
Yes.
格温多林 · 卡巴比克
Gwendolyn Kababik...
全世界都知道
known throughout the world
你的美貌和狡诈
for your beauty and cunning.
现在起 你是我的人了
And now you're mine.
我可以拿一下神鹰宝石吗？
Um... May I hold the Falcon Jewel?
当然 我的新娘
Of course, my bride.
谢谢你
Thank you.
暴君尤尔根！
Jurgen the Brutal!
卡巴比克兄弟 在格雷克有事耽搁了
The Brothers Kababik have been delayed in Gorek.
这些都是冒牌货
These are impostors!
- 冒牌货?  -抓住他们！
- Impostors? - Seize them!
不 不 我们可以解释
No, no, no. Oh, no. We can explain.
哦 不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no.
我忘了告诉你一件事
I forgot to tell you one thing.
我有男朋友了
I have a boyfriend.
退后 退后
Get back. Stay back.
- 走开  -退后！
- Stay away. - Get back!
退后！
Get back!
- 滚出去!  -我会烧死你们 贱人们
- Get out of here! - I will torch you, bitches.
我要烧花你的脸
I will literally burn your face.
我要去格雷克见那对兄弟
I'll meet the brothers in Gorek.
杀光他们！
Kill them all!
去抓住他！
Go get him!
夺回宝石！
Go get the jewel!
别担心我们 走吧！
Don't worry about us. Just go!
我的背包
Backpack.
走开! 我懂几何学
Get away! I know geometry.
我不是开玩笑 你们这些家伙 滚开！
I'm not messing around, you guys. Get away!
冰箱 我们就快没命了！
Fridge, we're gonna die!
有人想和新娘跳舞吗？
Anybody wanna dance with the bride?
你想来一块吗? 来吧！
You want a piece? Come on!
双节棍
Nunchucks.
太棒了
Awesome
我们赢了
We did it.
我们走
Let's go!
- 快点快点!  -快点！
- Come on, come on! - Hurry!
哇! 哇! 哇！
Whoa! Unh! Whoa!
看
Look!
- 那是斯潘瑟吗  -天啊
- Is that Spencer? - Oh, my God.
不！
No!
斯潘瑟！
Spencer!
- 哦!-哦！
- Oh! - Oh!
你到底是谁？
Who are you?
我是 斯默德·勇石博士
I'm Dr. Smolder Bravestone.
(强项: 凶猛 愤怒 砍头)
(弱点: 尤曼吉果)
斯潘瑟！
Spencer!
- 他让你骑在他背上  -谁 我吗？
- He says to get on his back. - Who, me?
迈洛！
Oh, no. Milo!
- 天啊 -他在干什么？
- Oh, my God. - What's he doing?
等等
Wait.
迈洛！
Milo!
干得好 迈洛！
Yeah, Milo!
上吧
Go!
我们来了 斯潘瑟！
We're coming, Spencer!
“让它沐浴阳光 ”
"Show it to the sun."
爷爷 宝石！
Grandpa, the jewel!
让宝石照到阳光
You gotta show it to the sun! Get ready!
快点 迈洛！
Come on, Milo!
- 走!-快点 快点！
- Go! - Come on, come on!
好
Yeah!
- 喊出它的名字 -喊出它的名字
- Call out its name. - Call out its name.
喊出它的名字！
Call out its name!
尤曼吉
Jumanji!
你们在喊什么
What'd they say?
尤曼吉
Jumanji?
哦！
Oh!
- 哦!  -太好了！
- Oh! - Yes!
哈哈 我们赢了！
Ha, ha, we won!
- 我们成功了!   -嘿
- We did it! - Hey.
放我下来
Put me down.
- 放我下来 该死的 住手!  -好的
- Put me down, goddamn it. Stop! - Okay.
这就是你要找的东西吗?  这个小东西？
Is this what you were looking for? This little thing?
外公 你们太棒了
Grandpa, you guys were incredible.
是的 这就是迈洛的功劳 他可是身怀绝技
Yeah, that's the thing about Milo. He's got a lot of skills.
迈洛和埃迪
Milo and Eddie.
这是在干什么
Uh, what are we doing here now?
哇！
Whoa!
干得好勇敢的冒险家们
Well done, intrepid adventurers.
你又救了尤曼吉的命
You have saved Jumanji. Again.
现在如果你愿意的话,
And now, with your permission,
勇石博士 请把宝石交给我
Dr. Bravestone, I will take the jewel from here.
我会用我的生命来保护它
I will protect it with my life and return it to the care
把他还给飞鸟部落的长老们
of the elder at the Avian Province.
所以你们的任务完成了
And so your work here is done.
我代表尤曼吉感谢你们 很遗憾 我们该告别了
All of Jumanji thanks you. And, sadly, this is where we part.
我不知道这有什么好遗憾的
I don't know what's sad about it.
我已经准备好离开这鬼地方了
I'm ready to get the hell out of here.
什么？
What?
真的吗？
Really?
伙计们 你们不会相信的
Hey, guys, you're not gonna believe this.
他说什么了？
What'd he say?
他说他...  -他想留下
- He says that he... - He wants to stay.
他说总得有人留下来守护这个地方
He says somebody's gotta stay and look after this place.
他说他75岁了 他才刚刚学会如何飞行
And that he's 75 years old and he just learned how to fly.
可是 那他就出不去了
But he won't be able to get out.
他知道
He knows.
哦 迈洛
Oh, Milo.
我感觉才跟你和好
I feel like I, uh, just got you back.
现在又要永远失去你了
Now I'm losing you for good.
“你不会失去我的 伙计 我会永远和你在一起 ”
"You're not losing me, buddy. I'll always be with you."
能成为你的伙伴
Being your partner...
是我这辈子最幸运的事
is one of the best things I ever got to be.
他说 “谢谢你 ”
He says, "Thank you."
不不
No, no.
应该是我谢谢你 迈洛
Thank you, Milo.
真棒
Yes!
- 保重 迈洛!  -再见！
- Take care, Milo! - Bye!
- 加油 迈洛!  -再见 迈洛！
- Go, Milo! - So long, Milo!
再见 沃克先生！
Bye-bye, Mr. Walker!
真不愧是我的老搭档
That's my partner right there.
我很幸运 有迈洛这样的朋友
Everybody should be so lucky to have a friend like Milo.
走吧爷爷 我们回家
Come on, Grandpa. Let's go home.
嘿伙计们
Hey, guys.
谢谢来救我
Thanks for coming to get me.
你要是再进来 就别想出去了 斯潘瑟！
You do it again, your ass is gonna be stuck here, Spencer!
因为我不会再进来了！
'Cause I'm not coming back!
大家都没事吧？
Everybody okay?
是的
Yeah.
爷爷 你没事吧？
Grandpa, you okay?
是的 我很好
Yeah, I'm good.
真是活见鬼了
Holy shit.
攻击  按方块键
Strike. Square one. Counterstrike.
底下那个宽宽的键吗？
The fat one on the bottom?
不 是R上面那个宽宽的键
The fat... No, the fat one above the R.
- 好的 -在二号键上面
- Okay. - Atop number two.
- 是啊是啊  -所以反击 反击
- Yeah. Yeah. - So strike, strike.
-好? -然后反击
- Yeah. - Counterstrike.
再来踢我 按O键
Then kick me. O.
我跟你说
Let me tell you something.
-老了就是……? -我知道 老了就不中用了
- Getting old... - I know. Getting old sucks.
能变老
Getting old...
也是种福分
...is a gift.
我有时会忘了这一点
I forget that sometimes.
可这是事实
But it is.
我还有什么好奢求的
What more could a guy possibly want?
你们好
Hey, guys.
今天过得如何
How was your day?
非常棒
It was really great.
没错
Yeah.
斯潘瑟还教我玩电子游戏呢
Spencer taught me how to play a video game.
(诺拉小馆)
还是算了
Oh, hell, no.
没事吧 外公
You okay, Grandpa?
没事
Yeah.
这里有太多美好的回忆
A lot of good memories here.
埃迪
Eddie.
埃迪 是你吗
Eddie, is that you?
诺拉
Nora.
-你好? -你好
- Hey. - Oh, hi.
你们好
Hey, guys.
-你好? -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
你好 哥们
What's up, bro?
生意怎么样
So how's business?
你也知道这里的情况
Oh, you know how it is.
经理半年前辞职搬到费城去了
My manager quit six months ago, moved to Philly.
从那以后生意就一直很冷清
Place has been kind of a mess ever since.
真正懂行的人实在是可遇不可求
It's hard to find people who really know how to do this.
好吧
Oh, well...
这事我不用说你也知道
I don't have to tell you this.
嗯
Mm.
需要我来帮帮你吗
So you need some help around here?
你说真的吗
You mean it?
我是说
I mean, I...
那我就太荣幸了
I'd be honored.
嗯
Well...
见到你真高兴 埃迪
It's really good to see you, Eddie.
我也一样
Likewise.
额
Um...
我要把这个
Um, I'm... I'm gonna take this
放到我要放的地方
where I was going and...
我去去就来
I'll be right back.
你们也一定要来纽约玩玩
You guys gotta come to New York too.
当然 我都等不及了
Yeah, I can't wait.
愿我们友谊长存
This team, forever.
友谊长存
Forever.
地久天长
Always.
友谊地久天长吗
Uh, always and forever?
-是的 大家常联系? -当然啦
- Yeah, let's keep close though. - Of course, yeah.
还有一件事
One thing.
我们能不能说好
Can we all agree?
以后再也不去那里了
Let's never go back there.
-我还以为早就说好了? -不去了
- We already agreed on that. - That's fine.
别走开 后面还有
抱歉这么晚了
Sorry it's so late.
是啊 每年的这个时候
Yeah, it's that time of year.
- 很多人的暖炉会出问题 -没关系
- Everyone's heaters are broken. - Oh, it's no problem.
我很高兴你来了
I'm just glad you made it.
暖炉就在这里
The furnace is right over here.
那是旧电子游戏机吗？
Is that an old video game console?
嗯？
Hm?
哦 是的 可能吧
Oh, yeah, probably.
这是我儿子的
It belongs to my son.
嗯
Hm.
好吧 我是个游戏迷
Yeah, I'm a big gamer.
我从没见过这样的游戏机
I've never seen anything like it.
看起来好像坏了
Well, it looks like it's broken.
也许你不该碰它
Maybe you shouldn't touch it.